[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Welcome living Mana Church family, we
are so happy that you are here with us
this morning or afternoon or evening or
whatever time it is in the part of the
world you are in. But we are so thankful
that you are here and that we are here
and able to worship God with you on this
Sabbath day. So, it's good to see all of
you here. Um, want to thank everyone for
all the birthday greetings uh that uh
were sent my way from from last week.
Uh, we definitely missed being here with
you guys live, but we are back now and
we are just happy to be here with you
and just ready to jump into the word of
God with you and just fellowship and
have a great time on this Sabbath. Yep.
Uh, and on this Sabbath, we're going to
be talking
about the sermon that I preached two
weeks ago. That's right. uh we're going
to be yeah reviewing the subject of
faith. So definitely uh invite your your
participation. We're going to have a
good uh recap of that message. So yes,
we are excited. Please put please put in
the chat where you're viewing from. We
want to say a special welcome to you.
And if this is your very first time
worshiping with Living Man Church,
please put a one in the chat. Um, but we
are just excited uh to be here with you
guys again. And what it's so exciting
because it is the month of April. It's
the month of April. That's right. And
what is special to Living Mana Church in
the month of April? It is our
anniversary month, April 9th
specifically. That's when we did our
first Sabbath live. Um, and so we are
excited to be celebrating all month um,
our anniversary of Living Man of Church.
We have been here for 3 years. Yeah,
that's really uh quite amazing. And we
just Yeah, we want to thank all of you
for uh coming along on this journey. You
know, we know that some of you some of
you are members, some of you are not
members, but you've been watching.
You've been with us from the very
beginning. From the very beginning. Um,
so means a lot to us that uh you guys
have
um uh supported this ministry, supported
the church uh with your prayers, with
your presence, and um we're just
thankful that we're up on three years
and we're going strong. The Lord is
blessing. Yes. And uh and the church is
growing. The church is growing. And you
have been there with us through the
highs and the lows. You know, we have I
mean, this is really church. This is
real life. We're real people, right? So,
we go through things as we, you know,
have been going through this journey
from the very beginning of this year,
really last year, uh, with, um, with
Sean getting sick and then losing him.
You guys were there and holding because
there we took some time away and had to
step away and you guys held and kept the
church together. So, we just want to say
thank you uh, for that. And um also um
just to those who volunteer, the
different teams and areas at um that all
that they do here for Living Mana
Church. Um you hear about the prayer
team, you even hear about the tech team.
Usually hear about them when something
goes wrong and we're thanking them. You
hear about them, but you know, we have
our slide team, our graphics team. Um
just our our small group leaders. I
don't want to miss leave anything out
anyone out. I mean there's but you know
who you are and what you do for living
mana church and uh we wouldn't be
celebrating three years if it wasn't for
all of you. Everybody working together
is what makes this church work. Yeah. So
we are thankful. We are really thankful.
Yeah. We definitely could not do it
alone. Could not do its Oh, we know. Um
I No, we sure couldn't. We sure
couldn't. I'm missing some. I want to I
want to talk about the great experience
we had last night, but want to just say
welcome to Vivian um from Philly. Looks
like she's looking um she is coming to
us from from Philly, Philadelphia. So,
welcome. And I don't know if I'm Well,
let's see if I go up high enough. South
Carolina. Got Christy from South
Carolina. Welcome here to Living Mana
Church from um Barbara from
Anguila. Marvin from um let's see from
Texas. Good to see you. Welcome. Happy
Sabbath to you. Got Dylan, South
Carolina Word Ministry. Welcome to
Living Man Church. MNA from Tacoma,
Washington. Welcome. Good to see you.
Annette from Kansas. Sister Annette,
good to always see you
here. Um, all right. Um, oh, Batswana.
Moses from Batswana. I want to say
that's the first time I've seen
Batswana. I don't know. Moses, is this
your first time? Maybe not. Maybe it's
your first time putting it in the chat.
I don't know. But welcome. We are happy
to have you to have you here. Uh, got
Leela uh from North Carolina.
So yes, welcome to everyone. Just didn't
want to miss those. Didn't want to miss
a one, but I don't see a one, so I guess
it's not Moses's first time. So, but
welcome. Good to see everyone.
Yeah. So, yes, last night uh we were uh
you, not we, you were speaking uh for
students at um Oakwood University for
their for their AY service. And it was
really a blessing. It really it was a
blessing before you got up to speak.
That's really what I wanted to talk
about too. like the students and you
know for most of you you know that we
both used to work at Oakwood University
and um both um um moved on
uh I and well for me in November and you
earlier last year but um just seeing the
students and you know just seeing some
of you know the students who I know um
and just other students that I don't
know I was like oh wow I really miss the
students to say that those students the
students at Oakwood university make that
that place an amazing what it is. Yeah.
Makes it an amazing place. Um and but
you know I you know of course I'm
expecting you to speak and I watch AY
all the time but they opened up uh with
just conversation conversation and they
were leading it so well and spiritually
touched my heart touched your heart like
they did such a great job and the people
were just insight in the word. were
willingly sharing. They were Yeah, it
was beautiful from the audience. From
the audience. Yeah. So, it was I don't
know if it's the first time they've done
that. I've never seen them do that
before, but I was like, "This is uh this
is nice." It was great. And then I got
to speak and that was so they invited me
to speak
and I um I actually got to share with
them the message that I shared uh a few
weeks ago here on meekness. Mhm. Um,
meekness is weakness. And, uh, it was
such a, I actually shared it a lot. I
would say it was probably significantly
different from this message. Very
similar, but I went a kind of went a
whole different route and really built
on the
uh, the Samson element. Yeah. And I love
that. Yeah. I just probably just need to
share that because I didn't do that in
this message. Well, you'll you have
other you'll have another opportunity or
do you want to share it right now? Yeah,
that's what I'm Okay. Okay. Share it
right now.
Yeah. Um,
so basically what you what what I shared
in that message last night that I didn't
share in the message on meekness here
was that
um
Jesus like
Samson was the strongest man that ever
lived. Truly the strongest man that ever
lived. Right? And this is not our
Sabbath school. We will pray before we
get into the study. Yeah. But I'm just
giving you a uh I can't say a sneak peek
uh because I'm not gonna preach this
here. And maybe I might. Maybe I might.
I'm just talking in my mind. Yes, I
think you will. At any rate, I was
sharing how God Samson was born to
deliver Israel.
So he was his birth was
prophesied and but no one knew or could
have suspected that it would be through
his death that he would deliver Israel
from the Philistines. Mhm. And and when
I said that, the the students were like,
"Yeah, that that really started there
because what I was sharing was that
Jesus voluntarily became weak." Mhm. In
order
to um to deliver us, right? And I shared
the parable of, you know, when a strong
man armed keepeth his palace, his goods
are in peace. But when a stronger than
he shall come upon him and overpower
him, you know, he divides his sp. And we
were I was sharing how Satan is the
strong man. Mhm. But Jesus is the one
that is stronger than him. Mhm.
But the way Jesus became strong not
became the way Jesus was stronger than
Satan was in Jesus becoming weak. Mhm.
Which is just kind of like wait what?
But that's how we that's how we defeated
Satan by becoming weak on our behalf.
Yeah. So basically what I was sharing
was that
um Samson God used God used
Samson to set up the Philistines.
Right? So by the end of Samson's
life, he's weak. He's lost his
strength. and 3,000 Philistines have
come together into one building to see
the man who was the strongest man that
ever lived who is now weak. What a
spectacle. This guy used to be the
strongest guy on the planet.
But it was all a setup to get
them into the same location, right? And
of course that Samson M
when I read to the audience how when the
text literally says Samson stood between
the pillars and they were like uh you
could hear you could hear them begin to
be like wait and then when I started
reading I had to have someone come up
and hold the mic for me cuz I had to do
it. You didn't have a lapel. Yeah. I
didn't have lapels. One of the students
came up and I was like, "The Bible says
Samson put his right hand on one
pillar." Mhm. And his left hand on the
other and they just like went wild.
Yeah. They went wild on that one. Yeah.
They saw the picture of the cross. Yes.
And the point I was making
was
Jesus when he died on the cross, it was
a setup to get the whole world to come
and see who is this man who was the
strong, who was God? Who is this man who
was the most powerful being on the
planet who has now become so weak that
he's on a cross? Let me go see him. And
guess what happens to all
those who end up going to the cross to
see this spectacle?
Just as Samson's death brought about the
death of the Philistines, Jesus's death
where there's a great earthquake and a
great rumbling, when Jesus dies, the
Bible says they that were in the grave
came up to life. Mhm. So it was
beautiful you guys to it was beautiful
to watch this message was yeah the
message was beautiful and it was
beautiful to see them the Holy Spirit
connect it connected with them and they
were like we're tracking we catch this
and of course you know at first they
were like where is he going where is he
going what does he mean weakness is
weakness but right but as the message
went on
light bulbs started going off and it was
just a beautiful
thing they were like come. Well, several
students asked for like your notes. I
was like, "Oh, wow. They wanted the
notes. They want to go study it more for
themselves." So, I thought that was
beautiful, too. But I loved it how they
be honest, they laid the foundation how
they opened up like they ministered to
our souls and then the Holy Spirit used
to bless them. So, it really was a
blessing. It was a blessing. Great way
to to start the Sabbath. But I want to
do Oh, by the way, go ahead. We didn't
get home till like 12:00 last night,
which has been a Yeah, we had a Yeah,
which is already a tiring week. Oh, man.
We were supposed to start at 8 and I
don't think I started speaking probably
till like
closer to nine. Nine. Yeah. Yeah. So,
yeah. And then then we just were talking
to them after so we ended up staying a
little bit later. So, yes. But it was a
blessing and wanted to do t-shirt
message. All right. I will walk by faith
even when I cannot see. And the Bible
verse 2 Corinthians 5:7. Yeah. So um as
I was just you know thinking about I
mean obviously I use this one today. I
mean I think a lot most of my shirts do
talk about faith but we are going to uh
be talking about faith today for Sabbath
school. Just you know recapping the
sermon from a couple weeks ago and just
doing a study on it with you guys. Um,
and you know, so that's just to me it's
interesting how it says I will have
faith when I cannot see. It's like that
is what faith is. You know, just we
cannot see. We cannot see. This is
something that one of the students said
last night that's bringing now that
clicking with me too right now. Um that
uh you don't you can't see the light at
the end of the tunnel. So you just keep
walking in darkness by faith. That's
what our trials are. That's what our
situations that we are going through. Um
um but then she was using how the
goodness and mercy are behind you. Um
she was comparing the uh yeah though I
walked through the valley of the shadow
of death. Um surely and then she closed
with surely goodness and mercy shall
follow me all the days of my life.
That's the last verse in Psalm 23.
Right. So it's behind you. Yeah. So the
goodness and mercy is still with you
throughout the process. you know, it's
like behind you, but it had been with
you going through this. So, when you're
having faith, even in the darkness,
goodness and mercy are with you
throughout this process. And even though
you can't see and you don't see the
light at the end of the tunnel, you will
get there. So, you have to look back to
almost give you strength to keep going.
It is beautiful. Yeah. Kind of goes with
what you're kind of goes what I'm
talking about. What I'm going to be
talking the students were just bringing
the bringing the stuff. So, I didn't
think about that until right now to
connect this to but but yeah. So
hopefully that's encouraging to you.
Like have faith when you even when you
cannot see. That's real faith. That's
the real real faith. When you can see
kind of like, yeah, I think it's going
to work out. I can see how this That's
not Yeah. That's not real real faith.
You can see. Faith is when you can't
see. That's what the Bible says. That's
right.
So, yes, we're going to get into our
Bible study, but I do want to let you
guys know that today is the last uh
message in the in the series nine
essentials for the time of trouble
series. So, this is It only took us nine
weeks. No, it started in December or
November. Yeah. Yeah. Started in
December. So, December. Not much
interruption. Yeah. Uh we are today's
the the the final message and um
we're going to you know all these
messages are in a playlist on the um on
our Living Mana YouTube page. So for
those of you who may have missed one or
two or several, you can go back and
even, you know, I'll let you know we had
difficulty with one or two messages
where the audio wasn't that great,
right? Um I think one where the audio
really but um I think it was the audio
was not in sync with the video. So just
close your eyes just don't look at the
video but listen yeah because the
messages were are very powerful. They
are and uh I've learned a lot about this
about the fruit of the spirit since
doing this series. So uh the Lord was
showing me stuff as I was putting these
messages together and today is no
exception. Mhm. So, uh, if you think you
know what temperance is,
you're going to learn some new stuff
today, right? So, uh, I'm excited. Yeah.
All right. Because you haven't shared
anything with me yet. So, yeah. So, I'm
going to hear it with you. Yeah. Yes.
Well, let's pray. Let's pray. Oh, you
want to pray? Yes. Sure. Heavenly
Father, Lord, I thank you for the
Sabbath. Lord, I thank you for this
opportunity to to share with so many
people from all around the world. Um and
we just ask that your holy spirit would
be with us at this time as we uh study
your word together in Jesus name. Amen.
Amen. Amen. All right. So uh please feel
free to interact with us. Let us know um
you know we're going to be talking about
the sermon on faith. And um if you watch
the sermon like go ahead and put in the
chat some of the things that really
jumped out to you in that sermon if you
remember. I hope you remember. Yeah.
Hopefully. Um but as we go through this
recap uh let's go ahead and you know
we'll we'll be asking questions we go
through. We'll see what what your
responses are. Yeah you're definitely a
part of this. This is our Sabbath school
time. So we want you a part of um this
discussion. Yeah. So um the entire
series has been based upon the the
concept that
um the sealing that takes place in
Revelation chapter 7 um is initiated by
the Holy Spirit. The Holy Spirit is the
sealer
and as
such what he is sealing us
with is the fruit of the spirit. Mhm.
So, we're being sealed with
love, joy,
peace,
longsuffering,
gentleness,
goodness,
faith, meekness, and temperance. And I'm
just brainstorming something right now.
If you see me, kindness or did I just
miss the Did you say kindness? We
started with You started with kindness.
Yeah. No, love. So, love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, gentness, faith,
meekness, temperance,
and now I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm going to
throw something out
here because I'm thinking about this. I
thought about it like a little bit this
morning and then I, you know, got
distracted on something else, but the
thought just came back to me and it is
this. Because some people argue, pastor,
the seal of God is
what? What's the seal of God? What do
they say? What do we say as the
Adventist church? What do we say? The
Sabbath. The seal of God is the Sabbath.
But this whole series, I've been saying
that the Holy Spirit is sealing us
with love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
temperance.
So, what I'm brainstorming right
now
is could it be that the Sabbath is the
sign of all these things?
[Music]
In other words,
is is the
Sabbath the symbol of love?
[Music]
Is it the sign of love?
Because remember part of dealing with
man I'm not going into the study right
now but remember part of the Sabbath
commandment particularly in Isaiah 58
is how we treat other people
right? Yes.
and just thinking
of what the Sabbath is.
Um, meaning like resting from
all of those things that we should not
be doing. I'm not talking about all the
things that we typically look look at,
but if you're being loving, then you're
not hating, right? if you are um you
know showing mercy, you're not you know
again not holding something holding
something against somebody or whatever
like you're just doing all of these
positive things and you're not doing
those negative things. You're resting
from that. Yeah. Gentleness stop right
treating others right the way they
should be treated the way they should be
should should be treated. goodness.
Are all these things
um can all these things be demonstrated
through a deeper understanding of the
Sabbath? They when you put them all
together, they make up the true Sabbath
rest. And I'll tell you why. I'm going
tell you why I'm thinking this, why I
thought because as I was putting
together my sermon
last night,
early this morning early this morning
on temperance
I began to see some connections.
Let me We're just going to stop right
here. Okay, we're supposed to be talking
about faith cuz I'm just going on.
You're going Are you about to go into
your sermon already? I'm feel Yeah. So,
we're just going to stop. Okay. You have
to stay tuned if you want to hear the
sermon. Yeah. Can't give it to you
earlier. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. All right.
So, so, but you guys, that's a study
that you all should pursue.
I'm probably going to do it. I might end
up doing that as my sermon next Sabbath
for like Mhm. an entire recap of
everything. I don't know. I'm talking
out loud. You are. I really am talking
out loud today. But we'll see. But if
you want if you want to kind of jump
ahead on me on that, go right ahead. Go
right ahead. Okay. So the whole idea
we've been talking about is that the
ceiling is the fruit of the spirit
locked into our characters
um in the time of trouble. And last two
weeks ago the focus was on faith. So 1
Peter 1:6 and 7, the Bible says,
"Wherein you greatly rejoice through,
though now for a season, if need be, you
are in heaviness through manifold
temptations, that the trial of your
faith being much more precious than of
gold that perisheth, though be tried
with fire might be found unto praise and
honor and glory at the appearing of
Jesus Christ." So the trial of your
faith, this verse helps us to
understand that faith is going to be one
of those things that are on trial in the
time of trouble. So remember when Jesus
said uh um when the son of man comes
will he find faith on the earth. So that
helps us to understand that the devil is
going to attack faith at the end of
time. Mhm. He attacks He attacks it now,
but the attack is going to be amplified
in the time of trouble. Yes. Right. So,
it's important for us to understand then
what faith is and
um
how to exercise it, right? How to
exercise it. Um and so we went into the
idea that we went to Hebrewsap 11:6
which says, "But without faith it is
impossible to please him. For he that
cometh to God must believe that he is
and that he is a rewarder of them that
diligently seek him."
So this is where the the the the idea of
faith really begins to I think
crystallize because faith is first
understanding that he is and that he
is. And when I was reading this text, he
is and that he is. He is and that he
is sounds so familiar to I am that I am.
And this is kind of what led me into
that path of
h why is why is faith believing that he
is and that he isn't. The text goes on
to say a rewarder of them that
diligently seek him. But it's almost
this play on words where you're
believing
that you're being asked to believe.
Faith is believing that he is he is.
Well, what what does it mean he is? And
that he is a rewarder of them that
diligently seek him. him. So that phrase
he is is really a reference
to the one who says
um or who is described as the alpha and
the omega the same yesterday, today and
forever
the I am that I am.
And this is a reference to the one who
exists, the self-existing one. Mhm.
Meaning he has always been, he is now,
and he will always be.
So
faith is a
recognition of what Revelation 4:6,
Revelation 4:8, who Revelation 4:8
describes as the Almighty, which was,
that's past tense, and is present,
and is to come, future tense. Yeah.
Okay. So then faith is believing
something about the past,
the present and the future. Yeah.
Because that's who God is. Faith in
God requires faith that is going to go
back. Yeah. Faith that looks forward and
faith that is in the present. And so we
ended up breaking up faith into three
different segments, right?
Yes. Well, I just wanted to talk about
the past part, but because I love and
have experienced that and started a
journey probably back in 2017 or 16
maybe, but had a a mentor
um a conference president's wife, Janet
Page, um who really inspired me to get
into um journaling, prayer journaling,
and and she led out with, you know,
Israel's biggest
um problem or issue was they forgot.
So writing, keeping the prayer journal
and going back and being able to visit
those areas and to see what God had done
builds my faith for the present. Yeah.
And um that's just been inspiring to me.
So I mean it's huge. Yeah. So for me and
for the future. Yeah. Mhm. for me. And
as I was putting together this message,
um,
and I went to Hebrews chapter 11 to look
at the Hall of Faith.
And some of the things that jumped out
to me was first of all that faith begins
with Abel,
right? It didn't begin with Adam and
Eve. So Adam and Eve are not mentioned
in the faith chapter, right? It goes
straight to Abel. Mhm.
And it's as if what the text is saying
is look, Adam and Eve had a face tof
face encounter with God. Yeah. So they
did not require faith, right? They saw
God face to face. Right. We have to see
God faith to faith. Yes. Right. So faith
begins with Abel.
And um
as as Abel as I'm looking at okay well
if if faith is remembering the past and
I'm asking myself okay well how did Abel
then remember the past and it hit me I
was like wait a minute so
Abel Abel had
to think back when he offered his
sacrifice by faith
he was thinking back he was remembering
back to Genesis chapter 3:15
remembering back to Genesis
3 verse
21 where his parents would have told him
what God did in the garden and how he
clothed them and how an animal was
sacrificed. And so he's thinking back,
yeah, this is this is what God
instructed. This is what I'm going to
do. So that's the
first example of faith.
The way you said that, I never really
thought about it like that. Like, of
course, Adam and Eve didn't have to have
faith because they they saw God. And I
just think like and they saw God. Yep.
It it makes their fall, not because it
was the first fall, but because of the
conditions like of the situation, they
saw God and they still fell. And it's
like their fall was harder than our
fall. Does that make sense? Because I
mean we we're coming from a deficit of
like we're not seeing God. So we still
have to have faith. And I you know I'm
just thinking about um how in heaven we
have a special song that we get to sing
that the angels can't sing. Adam and Eve
don't get to even I don't I don't know.
Well, they get to sing. It's the angels
that can't sing. I know. I know. I know.
But I was just thinking I know. I was
about to say that. But but they I'm
going to build on what you're saying.
They get to sing, but they still
didn't go through exactly what we went
through. Yeah. Just because we saw they
saw him. They saw him. So So even like
seeing him, we're the only ones who went
through that, I guess. See seeing him
and not seeing him again. And I feel
sorry for them because then they got the
fall and then they had to still live and
live. I mean, it's sad mentally. It's
Yes. Seeing him and not seeing him again
is not really faith. No, it's like I saw
you. I know what you said. I remember
what you said. It's it's remembering,
but it's not like by faith I have to
believe that God. So Abel believed by
faith because he didn't have that
experience, right? And so and it's been
that way with everyone everyone ever
since. I mean, yes, some have heard the
voice of God, but by and large, right,
we are acting on faith. Mhm. We are
hearing the word of God, right? And
faith comes by hearing and hearing by
the word of God. So Abel had to
remember. Yeah. Right. He wasn't there.
He has to go back to the past and
remember.
After Abel is
mentioned, it's then
um it's Enoch. So, Enoch is mentioned
next. And when I thought about that, I
was like, well, what would Enoch
have have uh what would he have to
remember?
[Music]
And I cannot help but think that Enoch
would have had to remember Abel's
faithfulness even unto death.
And so Enoch is like, man, this is how
Abel lived.
I'm going to live like that, too. I'm
going to be faithful even unto death.
And Enoch would have been so faithful.
In other words, Enoch was so faithful
that God said to him, you don't have to
die.
He's building. Wow. On the faith of the
one that came of the ones that came
before him, specifically Abel. Yes.
After
Enoch, Noah is mentioned. Mhm. And I'm
thinking, well, what would Noah would
Noah have thought back to Abel to Enoch?
Mhm. And it's interesting because in in
uh Hebrews 11
um Genesis
5:4, here's what it says. Enoch walked
with God and was not, for God took him.
So that's Genesis 5:4.
Genesis 6 verse verse 9 says this. These
are the generations of Noah. Noah was a
just man and perfect in his generation
and Noah walked with God.
So here you have the Bible describing
Noah as he walked with God. Well, who
did that before him? Enoch. The Bible
literally says Enoch walked with God. So
Noah very likely then would have
remembered back because remember faith
is part memory. Yes.
remembering what God has done in the
past.
Noah would have looked back and said,
"The past, it fuels you for the
present." Yes, Enoch walked with God. I
want to walk with God, too. I'm going to
follow after Enoch's example. And the
Bible literally says that Noah walked
with God, right? And so, what does Noah
do? He's faithful. He builds the ark.
And then he preaches. And how long does
he
preach? 120 years. And he's preaching
and preaching and preaching. And you're
probably thinking, "Noah, you still
preaching. Noah, are you still
preaching?" Come on, man. Like,
Noah's example was patience. Yes.
Patience.
Who is mentioned after
Noah? It's Abraham.
Now, we know the story of patience with
Abraham, right? God gives him a promise.
Hey, you're gonna have a son. Mhm. And
Abraham, but he always he he wasn't
always patient. Well, I'm saying he
struggled with it. He definitely
struggled with it, but in the end, he
was faithful. Yeah. At the end. At the
end, he believed. Even though he he he
wasn't even though he struggled with how
God was going to bring it to pass, he
never struggled that God was going to
bring it to pass,
right? But he put a little human put a
little human tried to help God out and
he ended up not helping him and making
it
worse. But but it still happened because
God's God's promises or prophecy is
going to happen even when we humans kind
of put oursel in it. Abraham never
doubted that. Right. Right. He never
doubted that. So the point is Abraham's
faith and patience he had to have gotten
from Noah's example.
Mhm. So what we're seeing is that each
example of faith that has gone before us
is is designed to strengthen us in our
walk. Yes. In our present walk of faith.
Yes. I don't know. I'm trying going back
to Abraham real quick. Go ahead. Well,
I'm just saying because he he he
believed it, but he kind of, you know,
put himself inserted himself into
different areas and kind of I don't want
to say messed up because you can't mess
up God's plan, but kind of, you know,
did some things that I feel like God at
the end almost was like when he asked
him to sacrifice his son, it was like,
okay, that was the ultimate sign of the
faith. Mhm. And he was like, "Okay,
Abraham, you're going to prove that that
other stuff
you weren't." I mean, he was having
faith through that, too. But he was
putting again himself into it, and he
didn't need to do that. And so, it was
like God almost used that another
opportunity to be like, "No, this is
Abraham is my faithful servant." He got
a little off course there, but look what
he's about to do here. Yeah. Yeah.
That's good. Yep.
So, I think understanding this, we can
then see that in the time of trouble,
what is Satan going to going to tempt?
What is Satan going to attack?
He's going to lead us to try to
forget how God has led in the past.
That was Israel's biggest mistake. That
was Israel's like, let's not do that.
Biggest issue, right? Mhm. So, so the so
the devil in the time of trouble is
going to try to get us to forget how
good God has been to us. Forget the
things that God has done for us and
forget the things that God has done for
others in the past. I'm bring this home
a little closer. Little transparency
here. This this what you're saying right
here definitely and I want to encourage
other well this is why we're here. We
want to encourage everyone but um
especially parents, right? because
sometimes they're in situations with
their with their kids and they
um their kids just aren't living the way
they would like for them to live or
they're just like, "Man, all that I
taught you is just out the door." Like,
it's just you're it's just gone or
whatever. And I just think about um you
know, as you guys know, we have four
kids, all four adults now. Um but, um
our oldest, you know, she went through
some some some stuff, right? And you
still have two babies. They they're 21
and 19, almost 20. They'll be 22 in 2020
this year. So, they probably don't
appreciate you calling them baby, but
but they still are. Okay. They're still
babies. But so,
um, whenever Yeah. Well, let's talk
about the babies. So whenever I go
through a little thing with the babies
or whatever, it's like I can look at the
30-year-old now and and
remember where God brought her and
that's so encouraging
to me now if I go through anything or
have gone through and I've definitely
we've definitely gone through some stuff
too, but it's like just having that
experience helps my faith now to be
like, you know what,
Come on. Yeah. God. God, you've already
shown me what you do and what you can do
and what happens through prayer. So,
just trying to encourage other parents
too because when parents do come and I I
do I what I'm just sharing with you now
is what I do share with parents um who
are just so distraught and so upset
about what their children are doing or
they're just not in the right space. And
I'm like just sapatismos chill rest.
meaning because
God, you know, you're praying, you're
walk, you know, you're praying and
you're walking by faith even though you
cannot see. And he is going to to answer
your prayers. He's going to answer your
prayers. Yeah. So faith then for your
children and other prayers. But faith
then is remembering all that God has
done in the past, not only for you, but
even for others. Right? So that's that's
one part of faith, right? That's part A
of faith, if you will.
Part B of
faith is the future,
the God of the future. And this is where
the promises of God come in. Right? This
is where the prophecies of God come in.
So faith is believing what God has said
is going to happen before it happens.
Right?
faith in the past. Hey, he's done it in
the
past strengthens.
It gives us reason to believe that
what's going to happen in the future is
going to happen. So, for example,
um
when I've been told I've been told
before I became a Christian that Jesus
was coming again. Yeah. And I was like,
uh I mean maybe if he exists, which I'm
not sure, right? But if he does, then
yeah. But you know, Yeah. We don't know,
do we? Mhm. We can't really know for
sure and I certainly don't know for
sure. So, I'm not going to give up, you
know, all the stuff I'm doing
on a hunch or a guess that Jesus might
come again. Well, you didn't know if he
was real, right? Right.
So, one
night 20
I'm sure it was 30. 30. Yeah. I'm sorry.
30. The oldest child is 30. 30 years
ago. Stick with that number and a little
bit higher. 30 years ago. One night. 30
years ago. Mhm. I got a Bible study. And
in the Bible study, I was shown the
past.
Babylon, Meo, Persia, Greece,
Rome, Rome divided into all these
different
kingdoms, the rise of a little horn, and
the changing of times and
laws. Here's what that did for me. I
like that re plant. He said, "Past
memories plus future promises equals
present hope." Beautiful. That That was
the equation. One of the equations. And
I'm cuz I'm seeing people even putting
the PM Yeah. plus FP equals PH.
Mathematic equations. We got the math on
this, y'all. Numbers don't lie, right?
Here's what happened to me, you guys.
Faith chemistry equation. Yeah.
when I saw the past,
you didn't have to tell me, or there was
no longer any, "Hey, I need to convince
you that Jesus is coming again." Because
if head of gold, chest of arms of
silver, belly, and thighs of brass, legs
of iron were true,
which as I looked back in history, I was
like, "Wait a minute, that did happen.
That did happen. That did happen. Wow,
God's word is faithful." Mhm. Then I
knew without a shadow of a
doubt that a stone cut out without hands
will come and destroy the image on his
feet and replace it with the kingdom of
God. There's no question. So here's what
happens. Faith in the past, right?
Seeing what God has done in the past
strengthens our faith in what he says is
going to happen in the future.
So faith in the past, God's word being
fulfilled in the past,
is his track record, his resume to say,
"Here's why I want you to believe me
about what's going to happen in the
future." Yes. Now, I want you to think
about this
because in the beginning for mankind, we
didn't know God's resume, right? So, all
we could do is be like, "Well, here's
what he said. a seed is gonna come and
he's going to crush the head of the
serpent, but the serpent's gonna crush
the the heel bruise the heel of the of
the seed, whatever that means. And as
all these, you know, as Abel goes
through his experience, oh, as Noah goes
through his experience, oh, wait a
minute, God's word,
it's almost as if God has been building
his resume with us, saying, here's why I
need y'all to believe me. Here's my
card. Check out my work in the past. M
so when you go, you know, you try to get
a job like you're you're an artist or
you're a you're an actor or whatever it
is, right? You got your resume. We want
that and they would they say you see
what's on the paper, but we want to
review we want to view your work. We
want to see your work. Yeah. Give me a
sample.
And you know what's so funny? You
guys call all the other gods and ask the
other all the ask all the other gods um
show me your work. Give me your resume.
M they don't have a resume.
Well, uh I am great. Their resume is
destruction. Yeah. Okay. No, they have
no resume. They have no record of things
they've done in the past, right? Mighty
acts they've done in the past. That's
what I mean. Like, it's there's nothing
there. Nothing. The record is, you know,
here's my
book. Here's my religion and my
followers. God actually has a
record with timestamps.
Here's what I did at this time. Here's
when I said that this would happen at
this time. Here is this time prophecy
that time. And that's why with our time
prophecies, the books of Daniel, the
books of Revelation. These books are so
heavily based upon things that have been
fulfilled in the past that we don't have
any need to doubt
that there is coming a movement that is
going to implement a Sunday law. Yeah,
there's no reason to doubt that. Yes, no
evidence. Yeah, there is literally no
reason to doubt. We should have our
faith in what our memory of what God has
done in the past.
should make it so that we don't have any
doubt, right? Well, how how is Christian
nationalism going to become a reality in
America? Listen y'all, trust me, Marxism
isn't the enemy, right? Communism isn't
the enemy of America. And that's not
what y'all need to worry about. What's
coming is what God said was coming,
right?
Yeah. And this is what strength.
Remember, there's a third part to faith,
right? So, we just looked at faith past.
We're now looking at faith pre uh faith
future.
And both of those things
combined now have an impact on faith
present. All right. Go ahead and say
what you were going to say. Well, I was
just going to say like how that was the
piece that really answered all of your
questions because you
were probably would agnostic. I don't
think you consider yourself atheist
because you didn't you knew there you
know you were you were searching right
so um but that brought everything
together for you the that you know had
the evidence the proof um and I was just
going to say as adventists like we those
who have like me grew up in it and
always just heard it and just took it
for granted and it could have been
building it's supposed to be building
not well building and sustaining our
faith throughout our whole process and I
think um for I don't for many that they
just take that for granted. Yeah. And
don't allow it to do what it's supposed
to continue continue to do throughout
throughout throughout our life. Yes.
When we share it and try to witness to
somebody and say but it really is to
just continually build our faith. Yeah.
To know that for sure we are not
believing and I think a fake God. Yeah.
I think for many for many of us we don't
even know what the future we couldn't
even explain Daniel too and that's the
easiest and it's easy but for so many of
us it's just like we're because you've
been brought up in something you're just
kind of like that's what I'm saying
taking it take it for granted like you
know the phrases you know what to say
how to say it but can you teach it
and I think the the the most difficult
thing about that that reality quality is
that Daniel 2 is so easy to understand.
It's really a basic history class. It's
a basic a world history class. History
class.
And that listen y'all, Daniel 2 is what
God used to convince Nebuchadnezzar that
he was real.
[Music]
Yeah. Nebuchadnezzar has a
dream. He's like, "What God? Huh?" And
then when the when the dream is revealed
to him, he's like, "Okay, now now I know
there's a God." He's still not following
him, but he's like, "Now I know that
there's a God. Now I know that the God
of Israel is real. It is a is a real
thing. The God of Israel is real." I was
just gonna I was thinking the same thing
and I was like like it's it's
interesting that is real. Okay, that was
Yeah, I never thought about that before.
He's real. Yeah, he is real. Israel. I
think I might preach something. I know.
I never thought about that. I just never
looked. Yeah, I just It just was
clicking. Is real before I could say it.
All right, so word play. Word play. Um
All right.
So memory of the past Mhm.
plus hope I mean belief in the
future strengthens your faith in the
present.
That's what now enables
us to presently walk in faith. Mhm.
So remember Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abednego, right?
They are brought before the fiery
furnace, before an image, which is very
significant.
Because at the end of time, God's people
are going to be brought before an image,
right? What kept Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abednego? Mhm.
First of all, remember one chapter
earlier, two chapters
earlier, in one of those chapters,
they're like, "Hey, we're going to stay
faithful." And what does God do? God
blesses them for their 10-day fast. God
blesses them. They're like, "We know God
is with us." But why did they even do
that 10-day fast? Well, why were they so
in why were they so convicted that they
were willing to do that 10-day fast?
Because they remembered others who came
before them. Wow. Right. So, now they do
this 10-day fast and they got they've
got the the sign that God is with them
in this 10-day fast. Daniel 2, they they
have the dream. God gives them the
interpretation. So, and in the dream,
what is he showing them? The future.
Yes. So when it now comes to their
present crisis, there's an image set
up and in this image or with this image,
you need to bow down. What is their
response? They're not bowing down. Mhm.
They're standing on faith.
10 toes down as the people say. I was
just going to say, why are we saying why
are we in sync today? What's going on?
No. Well, I feel like I'm honored to be
in sync with your biblical mind because
I'm not all I'm not I'm not that. But I
Yeah. So, and why are they standing
10 toes down? Why are they standing on
faith? Number one, because they're like,
we know, well, they've the past what
God's done for us in the past. We've
already seen seen the future. They're
like what the future is. And it's not
worshiping you. I'm good. Yeah. Right.
I'm good. And here's how good I am. Mhm.
When I say I'm good, I don't mean, you
know, I'm I'm not bowing down. That's
what they're saying, right? Yeah. Even
Even if
God doesn't deliver us cuz he delivered
us in He delivered us one chapter ago.
He delivered us two chapters ago cuz
there was a death decree. Kill everybody
because they can't interpret the dream.
Right? So, he's delivered us before.
But if he doesn't
now, yeah, we need to be remembered.
At first I was like, "Oh, no. They meant
reminders." And see, and remember,
if faith is about strengthening our
memory,
isn't that what the Sabbath is about?
Remember how we talking about do these
fruit of the spirit all come back to the
Sabbath? If the Sabbath is designed to
teach us to
remember, remember the works of God.
Remember what God has done and just the
glory of God. Remember the glory of God.
Remember the goodness of God. Remember
the faithfulness of Wow. Wow. W God's
love. Remember God's
joy. Remember the peace of God. Remember
uh the longsuffering of God. Wow. I just
got my sermon. And when you remember,
and I have a mental health note for
this, when you remember, when you when
you're doing all of those things and
remembering, that will lower any anxiety
that you're
experiencing, any depression that you
are experiencing because
remembering the goodness of God, the
glory of God, the faithfulness of God,
and just spending, the long suffering of
God, all of these things, and especially
on a day of rest, where you're clearing
everything else out that you're just not
dealing with any of that because God
says that we can. We don't have to worry
about the bills. We don't have to worry
about, you know, whatever that's going
to take us away from that space and just
remembering what God has done. Um it's
like that anxiety can't coexist in that
space. Yeah. And so that is something
that um can help. I was going to take it
too. I teach um or explain to clients
that um when you activate the vagus
nerve, the longest nerve and the nervous
system, your heart rate slows down. You
relax. Like so that's when we do the
breathing, that's what happens. There's
other points on your body rubbing behind
your ears. It activates that. But I was
just thinking when we do this and just,
you know, remember what God has done and
all of these things with faith that also
is activating the Vegas nerve because
you're not breathing hard, you're not
anxious, you're not afraid, you're not
experiencing the fear, you're just
sabot and resting with God. Yeah. So
there's just so many benefits. We are to
be rememberers. We're supposed to be
rememberers.
That's good. That was good. That's good.
So, so then they Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abednego, they remember the past. Yeah.
They knew it was coming in the future.
And it strengthened them to the point
where they were like, "Though he slay
me,
yet will I trust him?"
If he doesn't deliver me in this case,
it's all right. Yeah. I'm still not
going to bow down. I'm still not going
to worship you. I'm still not gonna, you
know, uh, distrust God.
The power of the past memory and the
conviction of what's coming in the
future, that is what strengthens current
faith. Yeah. And I think the reason a
lot of people don't have current faith
is because they've forgotten how God has
led them in the past. Mhm. They're
unaware or for they are uncertain of
what's coming in the future. And if
you're uncertain of the future and
you're and you're forgetful of the past,
your present is present is going to not
is going to be messed up. Yeah. Yeah. I
just had a memory because we're talking
about all of this
and I want to share it. Go ahead. Go
ahead. Go ahead. But I because you were
just talking about remembering what God
has done for us in the past and I just
hope this encourages somebody. But I was
just thinking and remembering I'm
remembering Clint
um I Joshua would tell our son he's like
the he's the timeke keeper of dates but
um I'm trying to think of the year
probably was is before the younger ones
were born so had to be uh 2002 2001
maybe but you we went to San Diego for
you to preach at a at a Korean youth
camp. Um, and we were very poor back
then.
I mean, we were just barely paycheck to
paycheck and sometimes not enough check.
But we were on a train ride home. Well,
we were about to be on a train ride
home. They, you know, you know, it was
both of us and the two older kids. And
when they were when they were the
babies. When they were the babies. And
um
we we wanted to buy them lunch before on
the train. No, before the train. Before
the train. Um because it was like going
to be like a five, six hour train ride
back. And we didn't have any money. We
didn't have any money in our account. We
couldn't buy them lunch. And the pastor
who brought us to the was taking us to
the train station, he saw that and I
think he purchased it or whatever. So,
of course, that made us really, really
sad and didn't know. I mean, we just I
think we spent a week down. You were
preaching to these young people and
everything and we were going back like
we can't even feed our kids. Anyway,
so we get home and we go to the mailbox.
Shame on me forgetting the exact amount.
I want to say it was 10,000 or not 12.
10,000. Okay. I think it was something
else that made it 12. Okay. But I think
Okay. So, we we went to the mailbox and
there was a $10,000 check in the mailbox
unexpected and um from a friend of ours.
From a friend. From a friend. So, this
is not a makeup story. Sometimes you
think
No, but sometimes like you know I was a
This is so real. Like this is was so
real. I mean our older kids could tell
you that. Not doubting other people's
stories. That's not what I'm saying. No,
this is real. Sometimes just like you
know that happened, guys. This really
really happened. I remember Were you
expecting the check? Did you just forget
about the check? I was not expecting the
check. No, what made it 12,000 is like I
think I was telling a little bit about
our business. You did get paid, which
was the the normal thing too. And so it
took it up a little bit, but I remember
going into the bank before direct
deposit and stuff and and they saw that
we were negative obviously. And then I'm
coming in there with like almost
$12,000. And I remember the clerk looked
at me like, "How did you do this?" But
but anyways, the point is talking about
all this is reminding me. I'm
remembering what God has done. So, not
that we're in that current situation
now, but I'm using that to feel my faith
now. Yeah. You know, and I don't think
about that all the time. I should think
about that more. That was before the
prayer journal and all of that. I should
really, but just speaking of this today,
doing the Sabbath school is reminding
me. We have a lot of stories like that
that I need to be remembering more.
Yeah. Um it's important to remember
things. Yeah. Yeah. So, so, okay. Um,
we haven't even included you on this
whole study. We just been talking and
talking. Well, they've been making
comments and I've been trying to mention
some. Yeah. But there's time.
So, I'm watching for your comments.
Okay. I'm watching for Yeah. So, think
about this now.
Um the reason why faith is remember the
past or the importance of understanding
that faith is remembering the past
uh understanding the prophecies or the
promises of the future
that bring you into a certain reality in
the present is so that when God
speaks you listen. Yeah. That's the
purpose. Faith comes by hearing. Yes.
And hearing by the word of God. Yes. So
God speaks. He tells you to do
something.
The the action of faith is h I remember
what he's done in the past for those who
obey him. I know that what he said in
the future is going to come to pass. And
therefore, what he says for me to do
right now, I'm going to do. Yeah. Right.
It's learning to obey and it's learning
to obey immediately. Now, now, yes. Now,
faith. So, Hebrews 11, now faith is is
substance of things hoped for, the
evidence of things not seen. So, I I did
a little play on words, right? Now,
faith. Now, faith. So, there's past, you
know, past memory, future promises, and
then now faith
is the substance of things hoped for.
The evidence of things not seen. Moses
did now faith like God told him step in
the water now. Now, now faith, which is
total faith because you're like, "Okay,
the army's behind us. I'm going to step
in the water and bring these people to
just drown in the water." You know, it's
like it was now faith. Urgent faith.
Urgent faith. But God said now and he
moved.
So in my message I was talking about how
you know when uh parents
um that's funny I saw Robert said
um so you know when parents
uh will say to their
children I'm only going to say this once
I'm only going to say this once and they
expect you to do what now? Obey
immediately. That's what faith is. Faith
is o is immediate
obedience. Faith is God doesn't have to
say it 10 times for you to do it. God is
trying to train us to hear his voice
once and do it. We think we're such
grown adults. We'd be acting like little
kids to God. I mean, he truly is our
father and we are his children and we
act like children and just the thing
about God is I'll say it again. I'll say
I'll say it again. I'll keep saying how
many different ways you want me to say.
Say it. Yeah. He wants to train us to
listen.
Because he wants to train us to act
immediately, right?
Um Simon says get up. When we play Simon
says, you
know, Simon has to say it once and you
do it and you do it quickly. Mhm. It's
the same when Jesus says something, he's
trying to train us how to do it. And the
reason why, and then we'll we'll we'll
we'll wrap this up right around here,
right? But this is kind of like the
whole punchline to this, right, is that
there is an ultimate command coming.
There's an ultimate command coming. And
that ultimate command is the command to
awake from the grave. Yes. So the Bible
says in John
5:25, "The hour is coming, and now is
when the dead shall hear the voice of
the son of God, and they that hear shall
live."
They that hear
shall live. Mhm.
Those who are faithful to God when he
speaks
once will become so used to obeying God
when he speaks once that when he comes
again and says awake those I going to
say awake. I said get up. You know, I
remember trying to get you up for He
will say awake a second time, but that
second time is at the end of the
millennium, right?
So all those we want to become one time.
Yes. Uh one time callers, one time I
hear one-times. I heard you. I'm doing
it. Mhm. Those who train themselves to
obey God's voice immediately will obey
his voice when he calls from the grave.
Guess who's not coming forth from the
grave?
Those who are like, "Yeah, I know you
said it, but I'm just not listening. I'm
not going to do it."
So the more you train yourself to not
listen to the voice of God in life,
those people when the voice of God calls
to come forth and he wants everybody to
obey. He does. He wants everybody to
come forth. But those who are not used
to obeying him in life will not obey him
in the grave. He'll have to speak a
second time. And when he speaks that
second time, which is at the end of the
10,00 years, that's when the wicked come
forth, God is trying to teach us to
obey. So that when he gives that
greatest commandment that has been ever
given to humanity, the most beautiful
commandment that has ever been given to
humanity, which is awake. In one word,
awake.
everything, death, sorrow, crime, all of
those things are gone with that one
command. But if we're not obeying the
commandments of God now, if we're not
hearing now, faith comes by hearing and
hearing by the word of God. If we're not
hearing now, we will not hear when he
gives that command.
The way God is training us to to be able
to do that and to
become one callers supposed to call it.
Um one answers one answers or one um is
becoming in train train to to be in
training for that is to learning how to
be so sensitive to the Holy Spirit. Mhm.
When the Holy Spirit moves or just it's
not even the Holy Spirit doesn't
um It's funny. I'm going to use an
analogy my my trainer tells me about.
She's like because sometimes there's
little movements that you can do. They
don't seem like big movements and you
don't think like you're building muscle
or growing muscle just by this little
movement, but the consistency of that
little movement actually is making you
stronger. Okay, that was from my
trainer. But that's the same thing with
the Holy Spirit. The Holy Spirit isn't
always pushing you to make huge
movements. They're little movements that
are making you stronger and stronger and
more sensitive to the Holy Spirit's
voice, to God's voice. And so that's
when you sign up
for the training and relationship with
Christ to really hear his voice, know
his voice, and obey his voice is through
the process of what the Holy Spirit
Yeah. is always leading and nudging. Um,
and sometimes we try to like,
not sometimes, a lot of times we try to
brush it off because we want to do what
we want to do. But the Holy Spirit is
just And the Holy Spirit is so gentle.
Yeah. The Holy Spirit obviously it's God
has the fruits of the spirit. So it's
gentle. It's loving. Yeah. Yeah. And I
think that and I'm Yeah. The movement of
that. Yeah. There's come Let me bring
this back to the Sabbath and then I'm
done. Done. Done
because I'm still thinking about it.
But if the
Sabbath is about us remembering,
we're remembering the
day, not to remember the day. All right.
It's a Sabbath. I'm remembering the day.
And I think that's what Allah Okay. So,
remembering the day. Yeah. The 24 hours.
Yeah. Yeah. It's about
remembering the God
who delivered you. That's why you're
celebrating the day, the God that
created you, that's why you're
celebrating the day. So on the day he
said to do it, Yeah. on the day he said
to do it, he says, "This is the time I
want you to remember who I am." And who
is he? God is love. The joy of the Lord
is your strength. Uh uh the the peace of
God that passes understanding, right?
All of these things, the fruit of the
spirit are the attributes of God
himself. And so in remembering, in
taking that 24-hour period to meditate
on God, you're remembering the goodness
of God. You're remembering the faith of
Jesus. All of these
things. And that's
why and I think you know when we say the
Sabbath is a seal of God it sounds for
some people it sounds impersonal right a
day right no no no no no the day is
pointing to the God of that day right
and the characteristics of the God of
that day which are exemplified in the
fruit of the spirit. Yeah. It's
beautiful. So that'll be message number
10.
Message number 10. Yeah. Because that's
really it. And that's where not
explaining it and sharing it in that
way is what makes people want to say,
"Oh, like Adventist, you're legalistic.
You're all about a day." No. I mean, no.
I mean, yes, this it's the Sabbath. It's
the seventh day. But when you leave that
out, this part out, then it does become
legalistic. Yeah. And that's not the
example we want to show to the world.
Mhm. Yeah. We want to show them this
holistic the whole picture. Yeah.
Yes. It's a day, but it's also about
these characteristics of the God. That's
right. That I want to introduce you to.
So, yeah, we could go on and talk about
this for longer, but we're going to
pause. We're going to stop right there.
But it definitely was a blessing, eye
opening, some things for me, a lot of
things for me as well. It's a blessing.
Amen. Amen. All right. So uh do remember
that this is uh I'm going to be speaking
on uh the the fruit of temperance today
uh at our divine service and uh it's
going to
be it's going to be by the grace of God
uh lifechanging. I believe it. I have
faith. Thought changing too. I have
faith the future, the past, all the
messages that you've preached before are
giving me fuel for right now to believe
that this is going to be a blessing too
because of God, because of what he does.
Um, so yeah, we definitely have um we
have a a membership transferring wanting
first reading. Okay, so we're going to
do that, but we want to we want to pray.
All right, let's roll this out. Heavenly
Father, thank you for this study today,
Lord. And just thank you for even uh
bringing thoughts to our minds, Lord, as
uh as we're going through this study,
unexpected thoughts, Lord. Um but that
help to enhance uh our understanding of
of the spirit of the fruit of the spirit
of the time of trouble, Lord, and what
needs what we need to be um um who we
need to be beholding, Lord, um and the
character that we need to possess, Lord,
during this time. So Lord uh help us
Lord as we continue in our study and I
thank you Lord for um uh speaking to us
through your word. Lord please continue
to transform us and uh bless us Lord as
we prepare to enter into our second part
of our service. Um thank you for uh your
love for us. Thank you for your spirit.
Thank you for your grace Lord. And we
pray all this in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Amen. Um we are about to do the
membership transfer. But before I even
um go there, want to also um let those
members, the members, official members
of Living Mana Church um that we are
having a meet and greet today at 6 PM
Central time and you should have
received uh a Zoom link into your emails
and um an invite to to join us. So, just
a reminder to if you did not if it was
missed uh or go back and look and um
want to make sure that you guys are
there just so uh we can uh welcome some
of our newer members and and um
hopefully we'll even have some of the
board members there that will be able to
to join us as well. So, it's for all
members. Yes, it's for all members, but
we're but we're going to be um
introducing new ones to you that we
didn't get to actually that have not
been a part of the meet and greet
before. So, please hopefully you will be
able to be there because we'd love to to
meet you and hear more of your story and
just get to know you a little bit a
little bit better. So, okay, with that,
we have a first reading for Sharon Fay
Johnson, who is leaving Granite Bay
Hilltop Church and wanting to transfer
here to LMLC. So, we are um excited and
thankful um to have Sharon Johnson here
at Living Mana Church. And also I'll be
sharing during church how you can um
transfer your membership. So I'll let
you stay tuned and and so you can get
that information if you are interested
in doing that as well. I'll also be
giving information about baptism and
profession of faith as well too. So we
are um just looking forward to um just
people joining the church and continuing
to come and so we are just thankful
thankful for that for sure. All right.
So, definitely stay tuned, share on your
social media. Um, and just, yes, share,
like, if you haven't subscribed, please
subscribe uh to the Living Mana Church
YouTube channel. Um, so do all that, but
invite your friends and family to
church. They will be blessed. They've
already, if they missed the first part
of the uh of our service today, what we
just did, you have to tell them they
have to go back so that they can hear
about faith as well. But invite your
friends and family uh to church and have
ask them to worship with you and we will
see you in the divine worship service.
Amen.
[Music]
Deep down in the South Pacific, there's
an Edenic island paradise that's hard to
describe with words. Its beauty is
breathtaking. Its climate is relaxing.
Its people are welcoming. Its culture is
enriching. Its food is fulfilling. And
its water is
refreshing. Perhaps these Melanesian
islands are best known in the world by
the water that quenches the thirst of
thousands of people each day. The
natural artisian water of Fiji is the
number one imported bottled water in the
United States and is enjoyed in over 60
countries around the globe. And while
most have never seen this beautiful
land, many have been refreshed by its
soft and smooth water. It is bottled
right at the source high in the
unspoiled rainforest of the largest of
the Fijian islands
vitile. As tropical rain falls upon
pristine rainforest, it filters through
layers of volcanic rock, gradually
gathering natural minerals and
electrolytes essential for the human
body. This life-giving water collects in
a natural artisian aquifier deep below
the surface of the earth, protected from
external elements and uncontaminated by
man, untouched by humans until you
unscrew its cap and put it to your lips.
Now, it's a little pricey in the States,
but here in Fiji, it's very affordable.
And we've been blessed by being hydrated
by it day after day. You see, water is
essential to every form of life. Every
living cell, plants and animals and
humans, depends on water. In fact, three
of the five quarts of blood in the blood
vessels of our body is water. And of
every 10 lbs of our weight, seven of it
is water. Without water to drink, life
is just
unsustainable. Water is also a natural
wonder. Its chemical formula is H2O,
which means for every part of hydrogen,
there are two parts of oxygen. Now,
oxygen is flammable and hydrogen readily
burns. But when uniting hydrogen and
oxygen into water, you have the liquid
that has the power to quench blazing
fires and satisfy burning thirst. Water
is not only essential for survival, it's
also satisfying for life. And in the
same way, this is exactly what God is to
us. You see, just as this Fijian water
fell from tropical skies to saturate the
soul of the earth, so too the healing
rain Jesus Christ descended from heaven
to earth to saturate the soul of our
lives and to revive and refresh our
souls. He is the heavenly rain and the
living water, uncontaminated by the
pollution of sin, full of the minerals
of grace and the electrolytes of power,
ready to fill the empty bottles of our
lives.
So, are you thirsty today? Have the
longings of your life remained
unfulfilled and empty? Have you been
drinking from the polluted springs of
sin and
selfishness? Or maybe you feel yourself
dying in a drought of discouragement and
despair, spiritually dehydrated by
family issues, health problems,
paralyzing addictions, painful
rejection, or plaguing loneliness? Well,
if so, hear the words of the living
water to you today. Jesus said, "If any
man thirsts, let him come to me and
drink. He who believes in me, as the
scripture says, out of his heart will
flow rivers of living
water." As good as it is, this Fiji
water can only punch me for a little
while. For Jesus said, "Whoever drinks
of the water from the wells of this
world will thirst again. But whoever
drinks of the water that I shall give
him will never thirst. But the water
that I shall give him will become in him
a fountain of water, springing up into
everlasting life.
And so today, let us go to the water
source. And as we do, Christ will not
only fill up the empty bottles of our
lives, but he will also extort us into
the world as living containers to share
the water of hope in a world that is
dying of spiritual thirst. So let us
come so that we can all go and that the
water of life can freely flow.
our bags and
stuff shaking.
Yeah.
Bruce is driving us. Thank you for
helping us, bro. You're welcome. You're
welcome. Yesterday, I was praying. Thank
Thank the Lord that he answered the
prayers. It was quick. It was fast
respond. Yeah. So many people had sent
words of encouragement, prayers. It
really held me up for sure yesterday.
Gave me power. last night when we
preached on baptism. I preached right
after this incident took place and I was
weak. Felt like fainting before I got up
to speak. But when I was behind that
pulpit, there was just there was
supernatural power there. All those
people came to the front, gave their
hearts to Christ. Many wet eyes last
night. The spirit of God moved in a
powerful way. So the the officer just
said that they found our stuff. Praise
God. Special thanks to this guy. So the
guy we thought guy who robbed us was
actually the one who's trying to help
us.
So many people in life, they look upon
God as one that's trying to rob our joy.
The God that just wants to make our life
miserable with a whole bunch of
restrictive burdens, but we don't
realize that the very one that we think
is trying to rob us is the one that's
trying to save us. Amen. Mercy upon us.
So we're in the police station now. We
can't really film here inside. We're
going to continue the story later on.
[Music]
I was
uh 14 years old. I stole a whole bunch
of things and I got caught and I got
arrested just like you, you know,
handcuffed. I had to sit in in jail and
I felt so bad. So, I know how you feel,
man. Today, I get to travel all over the
world and help people and share hope to
others. Even though I made mistakes in
the past, God still has a plan and a
purpose for us. Same thing he did for
me, he can do for you, too, man. Do you
know Jesus? You've heard about him
before. He died on the cross, man. To
forgive us of our sins. God has a plan
for you. He loves you and he wants you
to He wants to use you to do great
things. Let him change your life, man.
You're 17 years old. You can be anyone.
You can do anything with your life. You
probably felt like you had to steal so
you can get money to take care of your
family or whatnot. But when you serve
God, he's going to take care of you,
man. So, I want you to know that that we
love you, brother. God loves you, man.
All right.
Can I pray with you? Father in heaven,
Lord, I want to pray for my brother
here. Lord, this is your son and you
love him. You die for him and you have a
great plan and purpose for his life. And
I pray, Lord, that you would turn his
life over to you. That you would help
him to use his energy, his time, and his
his talents, and his influences to to do
good in the world. I pray that you'll
help him to feel your love and to feel
your forgiveness. And I pray Lord that
he and his family will be in your
eternal kingdom, but we never have to
steal, never have to grow hungry. I
thank you, Lord, for hearing this prayer
in Christ's name.
Amen. So, I'll be praying for you, man.
I'm not going to forget you, and I hope
that you won't forget me, too. And um
God loves you, man. Uh when are you
leaving? All right, brother. Before we
leave, just wanted to thank thank you
and and your wonderful team. uh
overnight we were able to find all our
all our possessions, most of it at
least. And that was very quick. Thank
you guys so much for taking the time
going door to door and just helping us.
It was a very devastating experience
yesterday. Keep you folks in prayer as
you continue to keep uh this community
safe that the angels will protect you as
you seek to protect others. I'm
wondering if I can just have a prayer
for you. And father in heaven, Lord,
want to thank you so much for your great
love and your mercy towards us. Lord, I
want to thank you so much for the
officers and the law enforcement, the
team here, SUVA, and how they quickly
responded and they did their jobs well.
But we pray, Lord, that you'd send
angels to protect each one of them. I
ask, Lord, in Jesus name that you'd
bless each one of them from the crown of
their head to the sole of their feet.
Bless this police station and everyone
that works here. We pray that angels
would be always in this place. And we
thank you for hearing and answering this
prayer. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Amen.
God bless you. Thank you, brother. Great
job. Thank you. Thank you. This is the
man who helped us. So, last night when
we preached at our seminar, we told the
experience of what happened and so
happens the deputy police commissioner
of Fiji was watching our program and he
responded and he called all his his
workers and uh told them that we needed
that they needed to solve the case. And
so, praise the Lord and uh the Lord used
him to answer the prayers of his people.
And so we just want to praise God for
that. Okay. So we just got a text on my
phone. Dear pastor Bula Vinaka, I spoke
with you a while ago. I hope you are
satisfied with the work of my officers.
I was unhappy when I watched your
grievance last night during the seminar.
There is a sale in my house attended by
the community members. I immediately
contacted my officers to immediately
follow up and I am thankful that you
have experienced the service we provide.
Haka, deputy commissioner of police.
We're very satisfied.
We're going to go back to the river to
the waterfall. The devil stopped us
yesterday, but not for long. Nothing can
stop God's work. So, we're going to go
back. We're not going to let the devil
win. Let's go. Told me sorry. You know,
when I was about his age, I was arrested
before
So, just about 24 hours ago, right here
at this exact spot, the devil stole my
camera equipment. He didn't steal my
joy. He didn't steal my peace. Tried to
stop God's work, but God's work can't be
stopped. So, we're here again. By God's
grace, even though yesterday he stole my
camera equipment, we're able to steal
some souls from his kingdom. as last
night over 50 people here in Soua
responded to the baptism appeal and gave
their hearts to Jesus. So the Lord has
already won the victory. The devil's a
defeated defeated enemy. All he can do
is all he can do is distract us. But God
has won the victory. Wow. What an
amazing day we had today. From the
tragedy of yesterday, we experienced
triumph today. Yesterday was a mess.
Today is a message. Yesterday was a
test. Today is a testimony. Yesterday we
were victims but by God's grace today we
remain victorious in Christ with all
that's happened we just want to thank
God and even though we had a difficult
time yesterday we still love Fiji Fiji
timeaka the
[Music]
naka let's
Oh, heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Welcome back living mana church family.
So happy that you are here with us and
continue to worship with us today here
at Living Mana Church. We are so
thankful that you are here. And if you
have just joining us for the first time,
um please put in the chat where you are
viewing from so we can say a special
welcome to you. And if this is your
first time worshiping with us, please
put in the put a one in the chat so we
can know that this is your very first
time. But we are so happy and thankful
that you are here with us today. It is a
blessing to worship with all of you from
all around the world. Um it is just
living mana church is is just a huge
blessing and um it is our anniversary
month officially. It's April 9th, but we
start celebrating early on April 1st. We
start celebrating uh my my birthday
month is March, right? So, my my
birthday is actually March 31st, but I
celebrate the whole month. So, here at
Living Bit Church, we are going to
celebrate the anniversary um the in the
whole uh for the whole month of April
because we are just so thankful to God
and we are three years old. We are three
years old. That is amazing of what God
can do. God is so faithful and you are
so faithful as well to him because he is
the one the Holy Spirit moved upon your
heart to even come and check us out and
then you did and you obviously were
blessed by what you were seeing and
hearing. So, you keep coming back and we
are so thankful uh to God and to you for
supporting Living Mana Church. This this
upstart, if you will, this this new
thing, this idea, this
experiment, you know, and it has went
from all of those things to a
full-fledged church. We're thankful to
the Nor Eastern Conference who gave us
uh our first chance because like we are
the first official online church of this
of of of the 7th Day Adventist Church.
And so we are just so thankful to God,
to you, the Northeastern Conference,
just everyone that has helped Living
Matter Church to be who it is and be
here for this long. So we are thankful.
But I want to say welcome to Lisa from
Vancouver Island, which is so Yeah, you
put it so pretty. I haven't been there,
but I've heard that it is so pretty. So,
I I want to I want to be there at some
point. I know I can't I don't get the
name, but I see the Virgin Islands. So,
I'm sorry I missed that. It went up kind
of fast. We have But welcome. And and
Regina, I believe from Brooklyn.
Welcome. Looks like Latoya is happy that
you're from Brooklyn. I'm assuming
you're from Brooklyn, too, Latoya. Um
hi, Zadina. So, good to see you. Know
that you are from my hometown, Pastor
Robels, California. Good to see you here
worshiping with us. Uh Sister Jerry,
good to see you um as well. And I
probably have missed some because I was
just talking away just talking about how
happy uh we are. Okay. And we also from
Europe. So I'm not don't know
specifically where in Europe, but you
but we got your your continent there in
Europe. So welcome here to Living Mana
Church. So good to see
you. All right. So, yeah. All right. We
did Vancouver Island. So, we just want
to welcome Crystal. Oh, so good to see
you, Crystal from Spokane, Washington.
Our sweet Crystal Cox. You are so dear
to Living Mana Church. You um and your
children and your husband, your late
husband was such a blessing to Living
Mana Church. Definitely here with us
from the very beginning making um Living
Mana Church so special. and Crystal was
our very first profession of faith and
so you have a very special place in our
hearts here at Living Mana uh Crystal.
So we're just so happy to see you. Uh we
have
Serbia, welcome. As you guys know, this
is an international church. So we have
uh members and viewing audience from
everywhere. And so we're just so
thankful uh to be able to to be able to
do this with you each and every week. It
truly is a blessing to spend the Sabbath
with all of you. And you know, and let
me do this one. Beverly uh from from
Florida, the Orlando area. Kiss kiss to
me. I always think I say that wrong, but
hopefully I said it. Okay. I know that's
in the Orlando area. So, Beverly,
hopefully we get to meet you for sure at
the convocation because it's right in
your neck of the woods, right there in
your backyard. So, we look forward uh to
seeing you. Okay, there's more popping
up. Let me let me do more. There's
Janice from BISE. Good to see you here
at Living Mana Church. Um, so good to to
have you here. So good to have you all
here. So, as we've stated, this is an
international church, so we have people
from everywhere all around the world.
But if you want to stay connected to
Living Man Church, which it's really
important to stay connected because uh
we are um a virtual church, right? So,
we don't see we don't go to an actual
physical building every week and see
each other every week in that way, but
we still can stay connected. And there's
several ways that you can do that. And I
want to um just really encourage you to
sign up to be able to do that. So, if
you're here in America, you will be able
to get text alerts so you can be
reminded of the programming when we go
live, um different announcements that we
um that we will have um throughout the
week. And if you haven't done so so far,
please sign up for the LMLC text at
855207-4107. Uh that way you can even
scan the QR code there in the corner and
that way you will be able to stay
connected with uh Living Mana Church and
get those text alerts. Also, Mighty
Networks, even if you're even if you're
getting the text alerts, you still need
to sign up for Mighty Networks. And
those who are international, you
definitely need to sign up for Mighty
Networks because you can't get the text
alerts. So, our church virtual home, our
hub, our home is Mighty Networks. That's
where you're going to see announcements.
You get to meet members there. You can
leave prayer requests there. You can
find out all the small groups that are
there, meet the leadership, meet other
church members and viewing audience, and
just stay connected. You can have
dialogue. It's all kinds of things that
can happen in Mighty Network. So, if
you're loving Living Mana Church and you
want to uh stay connected, be a part of
the things that we do here and just get
to know people here at Living Mana
Church, you need to sign up for Mighty
Networks. And that link uh was in the
chat. So, you will be able to do that.
And we are just so thankful uh to all of
you that you do want to stay connected
and that you are being blessed by living
me Excuse me, I can't talk right now.
That you are being blessed by living
mana church. And so signing up to get
text alerts and going to mighty
networks. That is how you are going to
be able to do that. Want to remind you
that we do have children's programming
lc kids and Locosc
uh 30 minutes before we do um central
standard time um before we start our
divine worship service. and they run
about an hour and a half. And so we are
just so blessed to have uh the
leadership uh with LMLC kids that love
working with the kids. And you know,
they're not just entertaining them. The
kids do have fun, don't get me wrong,
but they are teaching them the deep
things of the word. They're learning
photo theology concepts and are really
learning the deeper things in the word
of God. So, but they also do a lot of
the fun things that kids likes likes to
do with arts and crafts and they have
wonderful story time and music and all
types of things that the kids really
enjoy. So, if you want to get your kids
involved in LMLC kids, please uh send an
email to the the leadership team and
they will share with you how to get your
children involved with LOC kids. You can
also um just sign up for the text um and
you can just put kids to that 855 number
and there you will get more information
as well. So if you're one of your kids
to get involved, that's how you do that.
And if you want to become a member of
Elos of the Living Mana Church, you can
email Patrice at
living.live. She will share with you the
different the three different ways that
you can become a member. It's one you
can transfer your membership. Um if you
are already an an a 7th Day Adventist
and have a me and your membership is at
another church and you want to transfer,
you can do that. You can join by
profession of faith. If you've been
baptized, don't feel like you need to be
rebaptized but would like to join the
Seventh Day Adventist Church. You can do
it that way as well. Or you can be
baptized um and become a Seventh Day
Adventist uh and a member of the Living
Mana Church. And all you just need to
email Patrice livinga.live live and you
will be able to get that information to
do one of the three ways that you can
become a member here at Living Mana
Church. Also want to let you know that
Pastor Meyers does have virtual church
uh office hours and so want you to, you
know, definitely take advantage of that.
If you feel like you need to meet and
talk with the pastor, please just email
Patrice livinga.live live and she will
set that appointment up for you. Also,
if you have prayer requests and you
would like to uh send that into our
prayer team, just want to share with you
how um you are able to do that. You're
going to be able to send an email uh to
the prayer team so that they can get
your prayer request. Also, if you sign
up for Mighty Networks, there's the
prayer wall is there and you can leave
your uh prayer request on the prayer
wall. But if you if it's confidential
and you just don't want to put it out
there like that and just want to send it
to the prayer team, um just email
praymanana.urch or you can text with
that 855 number. Our prayer team is on
it every day. They pray over your prayer
request and when God answers your
prayers, you can send a testimony of how
God answered your prayer to that same
email. Um, and um, as you can as you see
that how sister Ammer reads the
testimonies of the answered prayers and
people look forward to that. That's a
highlight of their Sabbath just to hear
how God is answering prayers uh, for so
many people. And she can share that if
you would like for her to share that to
just show how God answered your prayers.
We would also like for you to subscribe
to the living mana um church channel, my
living mana on YouTube. If you are
watching on uh power of the lamb, then
please go over to the living mana
YouTube channel and click subscribe so
that you can also uh view from there and
that will help grow our living uh mana
channel on YouTube. you guys are doing
that because we are well over 6,000
subscribe subscribers on Living Mana and
so we are thankful that uh that is
happening and you know like I said today
this month is our anniversary month and
we have asked that you guys send some
videos in and I'm going to ask that
again. I want to we want to share and
show you uh the first uh set of videos
that have come in at this time as we are
celebrating. But I also want to uh put
that email up so that you can continue
to those who have not yet send your
videos in for the living mana
anniversary month. You still have time
to do that and you can send those to
coach777gmail.com that you can see there
on your screen. So, please take some
time to write that down. If you have to
come back after the broadcast is over,
you can do that just so that if you
would like to celebrate with us and let
us know uh what Living Mana Church means
to you, excuse me, and wish us a happy
anniversary. Uh please send in your
video because we want to hear from you.
But at this time, we want to hear from
those who have sent in some videos.
Hi, this is Angela reporting live here
at the LOC news desk reporting breaking
news on Living Mana Church. It appears
that they have just crossed over into
the third year of their anniversary.
Yes, their church anniversary.
Congratulations, Living Mana. Now, most
people still want to know why Ivormeer
started this online church. But Sister
Ortante, our first lady, describes the
church best as it is phenomenal. Let's
take a listen. And again, living mana,
we're proud of you. Congratulations.
Is asking, why do you meet online
instead of at a church? Ah, Kathy. Yeah,
it's a good question and it's a good way
to kind of for those that are maybe
watching for the first time or will be
watching for the first time, you know,
um there are uh many people that will
never step foot in the church. Right.
Right. Um the Living Man online church
is uh our mission is to reach the
unreached. It's to reach people who for
one reason or or another may have had a
bad experience in church.
um never stepped foot in the church, but
we get to come right into their living
rooms. We get to come right into their,
you know, wherever they're right on
their rights.
Yeah. Um and you know, we we're we are
totally fine with being a transition
church where, okay, I started online,
but now I'm going to a physical church,
you know, right? Um we have members, uh
praise God, we love online, and I'm
never going anywhere else. You've heard
it all. Yeah. So, uh people are getting
fed here. But the key thing about what I
want you to understand about this church
is that um our mission is to move people
in their communities to be light in
their communities. So it's not just
about coming to online church and just
you know watching the here and go out go
out and share. Absolutely. This is your
feeding place. So uh so that's kind of
it in a nutshell but uh you know I think
it's a good question because it's a it's
a new thing. It's a new thing. It's a
great question and But by the way, the
fellowship that we have amongst our
members, you took it right. It it's
people we've never met 25 years in
ministry and I people we've never met in
person. Never ever. Y'all make me feel
loved. Y'all make me cry in good ways.
Y'all make me uh You make us feel loved.
Make us cry in good ways. Like we just
we love you and we feel the love. And
it's not just for us. the members
amongst each other feel the the love
between each other and so it's just it's
phenomenal. Yeah. Like it's just
amazing. So it's not for everybody. You
know, we get that there people a lot of
people need that physical uh you know I
have to physically touch you interaction
but uh you know again it not all things
are for everyone right so but this has
been a blessing to a whole lot of people
and it's been a blessing to us and um
you know it's uh we believe the Lord is
doing something uh unique and mighty
with this church. So, you know, praise
God for that. Amen.
Happy anniversary, Alc family. My name
is Sandra Silus, and I'm one of the
moderators for the gym adult Sabbath
school lesson on Friday evening. There's
nothing like having our members who join
us to share with us what the Holy Spirit
has impressed them as they study the
lesson through the week. It's a
quarterly lesson put out by the SDA
church. So, no matter where you are in
the world, we're all studying the same
lesson. Please take time to join us. We
would love to hear from
you. Happy anniversary, Living Mana.
It's been three years since we started
this online church. We pray together. We
laugh together. We've cried together.
But the one thing that we're all doing
together is we're headed towards Jesus
together.
Happy anniversary, Living Mana Online
Church family. We love each and every
one of you. God
bless. This is Tina Whitehead from the
Gems and Adult Sabbath School. Just
jumping on to wish you guys a happy
anniversary and not only to you but to
the entire church. We have made it for
three wonderful years. Looking forward
to seeing you guys in Orlando for the
convocation. God bless and
goodbye. That was just such a beautiful
video. We I when I first watched it, I
was like, "Oh, this is so amazing." and
just to hear from some of you the
blessing that Living Mana Church has
been. Um, and so please send in your
videos as well because we want to
celebrate with you. This is just an
amazing thing that God has done having
Living Manage Church here for three
years. Um, and we are still going. We
are so thankful for all that he has
done. Um, part of that is we have more
have created more ministries. You guys
have created more ministries, I have to
say. And the women's ministry has
something amazing coming up on April
13th. It is the cook off. And I just
want to share more about that with you
just how you can definitely so you don't
forget and we'll tune in for that. But
the women's LLC's women's ministry
invites you to a live cook off Sunday,
April 13th at 700 p.m. Central time on
Zoom. Several of our sisters have
accepted the seven ingredient challenge
and we'll be preparing a healthy tasty
meals right before our eyes. While the
while they cook um we'll be sharing
helpful tips on healthy eating and there
will be a live question and answer
session uh where you can ask questions
and join the conversation. Let's all
come out to support our sisters, learn
something new, and enjoy the evening of
fun food and fellowship. That sounds
like fun. And um I kind of want to be a
part of that. I I'm thinking I have a a
dish that I think is seven ingredients
that I think will be fun to share. So, I
want you to be a part of it, too. So,
please don't forget Sunday, April 13th,
700 p.m. Okay, I said central, but
that's Eastern. Glad that I did look at
that because I sure did say central. So,
Eastern time, 700 p.m. Eastern time. So,
that's pretty cool. Just seven
ingredients. Can you make something
really, really tasty and healthy with
just seven ingredients? Will come and
find out. And this is a woman's ministry
event. So, we just love that our women's
ministry is active um and just doing um
amazing things um here at Living Mana
Church. Also, just want to update you on
the convocation. It's not really an
update, it's the same, but just to
remind you, I guess I should say that
the convocation has moved to October
30th to nove November 2nd. And yes, we
will be in Kiss Me, Florida. that's in
the Orlando area. And so we want you to
be there. We want to meet you. And I
think we're trying to do something
similar actually at the convocation um
close to like this cookoff similar to
that. Excuse me. Where Pastor Myers is
going to be involved in it too because I
always tell people he's just as good of
a cook as he is um a preacher. So
believe it or not, he is the cook of the
home and I think he's going to be doing
uh some amazing things there at the
convocation. But you have to come and
check it out. You have to be there to be
able to experience it. Um, and there's
going to be others who are amazing cooks
that are going to do some amazing
things. So, you don't want to miss the
convocation. It's going to be fun. It's
going to be uh, of course, spiritfilled
the fellowship. Uh, we're going to be
still going deep in the word and in
prayer. It is just going to be an
amazing experience. So, you need to
register, sign up, and prepare. Put it
on your calendar. Start making the
preparations now. But if you need more
information, please e email convo@
livingmana.urch or you can scan the QR
code there that you see on your screen.
So we are excited and looking forward uh
to seeing you there. Also again just
want to remind you guys that because we
are an international church that means
we go all around the world and because
of that the whole world doesn't speak
English as you all are very much aware
and so we want to go around the world
with this message of uh the gospel in
the languages of the world and so we
were been blessed here at Living Mana
Church because of your faithfulness to
be able to purchase uh a system that
allows us to translate Pastor Meyer's
sermons and to seven different
languages. Um, and so we are really
going to be perfecting that within this
next year. I mean, it's already started,
but we just want to grow and get better
at that. We have an editor that edits
the sermons and even the
um the the slides into the language. And
so, we just want to give you a taste of
what that looks like. So, if you're
wanting to support uh LMLC Global with
your financial gifts, please please do
so. But we want to show you what that
looks like. And uh I'll give you more
information after you. Um we have
Spanish today. So you can hear Pastor
Meyers preaching the message in Spanish.
[Music]
signific
forch.
So that is what LMLC global looks like.
Um and that today was in Spanish and
there is a link so you can go um on to
YouTube channel for LMLC Global and
check out the different languages that
we have there. But if you know someone
that speaks any of those languages,
please share these messages with them.
Uh that is the purpose of LMLC Global so
that they will even share it with others
within their community that speaks that
same language as
well. Want to um this will I'm yes this
will be the last time I'm going to
remind you guys of this but are just to
give you this information. If for if for
any reason you have not received your uh
tax receipt from 2024 for your giving to
hear from Living Mana Church, please
email our intram treasurer. Um and I'm
going to give you that email here
shortly. Um here it is treasure living
mana.live. Please email her there and
you will be able to get information or
get she will be able to get you your
receipt to you by at this late date it
would be through email. But if for some
reason you have not received it, you
should have received it. But if not,
please email our treasure at that email
there. I know I received I we received
ours this week. So they've definitely
been going out and um I know many have
received it. So but if there is an
issue, please email our treasurer
there. We just want to again say thank
you for giving and supporting Living
Mana Church in these last these past
three years. You have been such a
blessing. Um God has just put it on your
heart and you have responded and we
thank you. You help Living Mana Church
do all of the things that we are doing
through the power of God. Um we are able
to have the type of equipment we need uh
to be um to have this professional look
that we do to be online and to just go
out into all of the world. And if
there's an issue and we are a needing to
purchase something else to be able to
sound better, look better, we are able
to do that because of you, because of
your giving. So again, if you would like
to continue or start supporting living
mana uh church, you can do that by going
to
adventistgiving.org. This is how you can
do it virtually. You can click in the
right hand um corner and you will be
able to get a tithe envelope, a virtual
tithe envelope. There you can um you'll
see so many different categories, but
you can give your tithe. You can give
your local uh church offering and there
are there's a place where you can give
to the benevolence fund where we're able
to help people who are in need um when
they're requesting some assistance. Your
tithe goes to the to the Northeastern
Conference which helps support that
conference and the worldwide church.
your local church giving to our local
church budget helps to support Living
Mana Church and the things that we are
doing here with Living Mana Church. So,
we just um really thank you for giving
and we are so grateful for your uh
faithfulness to God and to supporting hi
his work that goes around all of the
world. That is one way that you can give
or you can mail in uh your tithe and
offering. Um, you can do that by sending
it to PO Box 428, Owens, Crossroads,
Alabama
35763. You can send that in and please
put a note in there to say what's for
tithe and what is for offering or if
it's for uh the benevolence fund. And
you will see so many different
categories uh on that tithe envelope.
that if you know specifically or to
support Living Mana Global, just let us
know where you would like uh those funds
to go and we will make sure that it goes
to the appropriate place. So again, we
just thank you for your faithfulness
through your financial gifts, through
your prayers, through your attendance,
through talking about Living Manage
Church, sharing the videos with your
friends, uh letting them know that there
is an online church where they can be
spiritually blessed, find a church
family, connect with people, um and just
have a great experience. And that is
what you do for us. And so we are just
very thankful. But would you please bow
your heads with me as we come to God in
prayer just thanking him again for his
faithfulness and his goodness to all of
us.
Heavenly Father, Lord, just want to just
thank you once again for your Lord, just
who you are and what you do and how you
um just make Living Mana Church, an
online church, be a community where
people can become come to and be healed
and learn uh your the deep things in
your word and experience an amazing uh
prayer journey here with you, Lord, and
just be blessed. And it's all because of
you because it sounded pretty well my
words that I thought was wow that sounds
pretty crazy like how's that going to
work and what conference would go for
that those were my I lacked faith God I
lacked complete faith at that time but
you have proven to me that look with you
with you all things are possible and you
have turned this idea this experiment
into a full-fledged church that blesses
people all around the world Lord I want
to pray right now for every family um
that is that is going through um
marriage issues, parenting issues, just
relationship issues in general. And I
just pray for them. I pray for those who
are going through health issues. Lord,
those who are grieving uh thinking of
our dear brother Elco who is grieving uh
the loss of his mother this week and he
is such a blessing to Living Mana Church
uh through the prayer team and leading
out in the men's ministry and uh he's
been on several times just leading out
on Sabbath mornings in prayer. And so
Lord, I just pray that you will be with
him, bring comfort to him and his family
as they are going through this uh
grieving experience experience losing
his mom. And Lord, also want to lift up
sister Anne. She's having some health
issues. She produced that amazing video.
Um and so I'm just praying that you will
bring healing to her as well. Give her
peace and comfort um at this time as as
she is um in the process of healing,
Lord. And so Lord, I just again thank
you for this Sabbath. Thank you for what
you have done for this church. Want to
lift up Pastor Meyers and the message
that he is going to bring that you have
given to him today. Lord, let it move
upon the hearts of every hearer, every
listener that will hear this message
today and in the future, Lord, as they
go back and listen to the replay. Lord,
I thank you again in Jesus name.
Amen. I stood and stared from a
distance.
couldn't understand how this one man,
bruised and blistered, would stand with
taunts and
whispers. I felt sick just as a
witness. Who could deserve this? What
did we miss? I'd seen death before, but
not death like this. The Jews called him
a savior. I guess the Romans thought
not. What pillar stands that a perfect
man that washed feet with his own hands
should be lost? Why does the crowds cry
sound like
victory? They celebrate as they serenade
his misery. They thought him a king and
yet he wears such in glorious glory. The
crisscross trunks of torture are raised
to the sky. This cross clenching an
orchard of new
life. One last breath he finally
cried. It is finished.
Such words beg the
question, is death all I
witnessed? Perhaps the prophets and
pages had something else envisaged that
this self-sacrifice fought life along
with it. But this life claims dominion
over death's very
existence. I stood and watched from a
distance. One woman, heartbroken,
reminiscing, is greeted by
angels. I watch her shock as she
listens. For the tomb that bound eternal
love from its mission is broken open.
Love's unrestrained
resistance. The house of death is put to
rest. It's done with its persistence.
The bindings of sin have run thin. Its
captives cry good riddance, but their
debts are nothing less but for the means
of delivering.
The thorns are outgrown by the rows in
between. The constraint on our souls are
torn at the seams. And every inkling of
darkness is overwhelmed by peace. For
this light's illumination has nothing
beyond
reach. And as for this heartless death
which I bore witness, one thing is
crystal
clear. It is finished.
[Music]
There will be
mountains that I will have to climb.
And there will be
battles that I will have to
fight. But victory or
defeat, it's up to me to
decide. But how can I expect to win if I
never try?
I just can't give up
now. I've come too far from where I
started
from. Nobody told me the road would be
easy. And I don't believe he's me.
Never said there wouldn't be
trials. Never said I would
afford. Never said that everything would
go the way I wanted to go.
But when my back is against the wall and
I feel no hope is
gone, I'll just lift my head up to the
sky and say, "Help me to be
strong. I just can't give up
now. I've come too far from where I
started from.
[Music]
Nobody told me the road would be easy.
And I don't believe he's brought me this
far to make
me. I know you didn't bring me out here
to leave me
lonely. Even when I can't see
clearly, I know that you are with me. So
I
[Music]
can't give
up. I've come too far from where I
started from.
Nobody told me the road would be easy.
And I don't believe
[Music]
he's said I can't give up.
I just can't give
up. I've come too far from where I
started from.
[Music]
the road would be easy and I don't
believe
he's
[Music]
free to where I started
from. Nobody told me the road would be
easy. And I don't believe he's brought
me this far to leave
me. And I don't believe he's brought me
this far to leave
me. And I
don't
me to leave me.
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged or alone or
anxious, you don't have to face life
struggles alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy. and find
grace to help in our time of
need. The Lord is close to the
brokenhearted and saves those who are
crushed in spirit.
[Music]
Greetings saints of the most high God
and welcome to another edition of living
manners prayer and praise time. So happy
to be here with you. Here with my lovely
bride Amra as always. And listen, Living
Man of Family, we are happy and excited
to be able to serve you in this amazing
capacity. Shout outs to everybody that's
watching us from everywhere today. We
saw you in the chat earlier when First
Lady was doing the uh announcements and
the welcome. So glad you could be here
with us. We love y'all and want to thank
y'all for all of your prayers. Um want
to kind of get right to business today.
doing some special shout outs and stuff,
but Amry has a lot of praise reports.
We're excited about that because I mean,
we don't we we want to be about the good
news, you know, for those of you who
probably tune in and watch your local
news, you know, they love focusing on
the negativity, right? Exactly. Not
here. We're gonna tell what the Lord has
done. Shout out to you, Brother Clint. I
see you in the chat right there, Sister
Christie, South Carolina. Hallelujah.
Amen. And look who's back. Sister Ayana,
we missed you last week, but you are
back. Mighty Warriorette in the chat.
You and your crew encouraging and
praising. And listen, saints, y'all
watching. Y'all been kind of lazy with
the with the prayers in the chat today.
I'm just, you know, just saying. Uh,
we're here. So, if you have prayer
requests, um, put them in the chat. I
mean, I would have liked to call more
earlier, but now we're going. So, um,
I'll just get the ones that I did get.
And Christina
No, go ahead. Cuz you know what though?
I really have a special shout out. Can I
do a special shout out? Yes. We have a
very special birthday
today. Now, this was a birthday
announcement from social media. So, if
it's incorrect, I apologize. But if it
is correct, happy birthday to our very
own Living Mana online church secretary,
Patrice Delisser.
What? Yes. According to social media,
today is Patrice's birthday and we want
to say a special happy birthday. We love
you, sister. Everyone, please.
Well, well, happy birthday, Patrice.
this is your birth because I mean I've
been texting with the with the with the
with the tech team and I didn't know
anything about a birthday. Well, I got a
notification on my phone and I did not
want this time to go by without wishing
Patrice a very happy birthday. So, if
y'all could wish her a happy birthday in
the chat. I don't know if she's here
today. She might be celebrating, but
Well, happy birthday, Sister Patrice.
Praise God for that. And if it's not,
whenever it is, we're gonna do it again.
So, but happy birthday from the heart
today. Yes. Amen. Amen. Now, let me get
back to these shout outs. Okay. Sorry.
Um, Brother Elco, um, man, listen, we
want to definitely shout out Brother
Elco. First lady already did, but
Brother Elco was on post today. I mean,
he was serving even though he's his
heart is heavy and he's grieving. We
just want to say we love you and we
thank God for you, my brother. Uh,
continue to stand by you and support
you. uh and and want to be here for you
any way we can. Also, Sister Angela uh
who is currently in the hospital and I
believe she's watching. Sister Angela
been dealing with some health issues and
we want to continue to pray for you and
Sister Angela's special ops team. You
know, they have been faithful from day
one, continuing to support and pray for
Angela. Y'all be encouraged. The Lord is
using you continually. Uh be strong.
You've seen him bring Candela through a
lot of storms. So, don't be discouraged.
Don't feel like uh he's not listening
and you're not making a difference. You
are. You are a saint. Want to shout out
Sister Sylvia Martin if you're watching.
Sister Sylvia, we love you. We miss you.
All of our uh uh living man of family
down in San Jose down in the East Bay
area. Elder Drewa, uh Sister Andrea,
Lady Daniela, shouting y'all out.
Brother, you know, everybody we met down
there and we know down there and love
our family there.
Brother Oscar, if you're watching, God
bless you. Amen. Amen. And I want to
also send a special shout out to Sister
Annette Rivas. If y'all attended Power
Wednesday this week, then you saw she
hosted and and just so cheerful and
inspiring and encouraging everybody.
Sister Annette was going through a
serious storm at the time. And to look
at her, I was just sitting back just
watching, you know, because I'll watch
and see what the leaders are doing and
how they're ministering. She was just
ministering so powerfully and lively in
the spirit of God and just had a big old
smile on her face and I was thinking,
"Wow, she's going through that terrible
trial, but yet she's here trying to lift
up somebody else." So saints, I tell
you, one of the ways to get the victory
really to walk into the victory that's
ours
is focus on someone else and how you can
be used to help someone else even when
you're going through. I love what Sister
Atante was talking about this morning.
First lady was talking about some of the
things that the students were saying at
Oakwood last night. You know, um,
goodness and mercy shall follow you all
the days of our life. You when we study
Ephesians chapter 6, we see the whole
armor of God. There's the belt, there's
the shoes, there's the helmet, there's
the breastplate, you know what I mean?
There's the sword of the spirit, there's
the shield of faith. There's not one
part of that armor to cover your
back, but goodness and mercy got you.
Can you say amen? That's a good That's a
good thing to know. God didn't give us a
piece of armor for our backs. He gave us
He give us goodness and mercy to cover
us. They shall follow us all the days of
our lives. So, praise God. Angela in the
chat. Yes, she's there. Okay. She
promised us that she would be watching
and we'll be praying for her. So, we we
love you, Sister Angela. And one more.
Sharon Faith Johnson, thank you uh for
all that you do for the Lord. So glad
that you're now coming in as a member of
Living Mana Church. that thing you saw
Angela do with the news. You know, we
have more than one news correspondent
here. You know, Sharon Fay Johnson is an
awesome news correspondent. She does
some beautiful things. We did a surprise
birthday uh love bomb for Sister Joanne.
And Sharon Fay got right into the uh the
character of the news uh lady. And so
Sharon Fay, come on in. I got some
ideas, some things we can use for sister
if you were willing to work together
with us. And I know you are. Praise God.
One more shout out and then I'm gonna um
say this. Uh I'm going to give it over
to my lovely brides. I want to shout out
the Living Man of Tech team. Oh my lord,
what an amazing bunch. I mean, Sister
Patrice, Brother Gavin, Brother Josh, I
mean you guys, Brother Colin, who I'll
be seeing tomorrow by the grace of God
right here. And we're gonna spend a
little time together. Praise God. And uh
we got some amazing things coming. And
so, thank God for our tech team. team.
They're doing an amazing job. Believe
me. Let us not take for granted.
Sorry. I was just going to say we want
to shout them out. Not just when things
go wrong. Yeah. When everything goes
right, things go right a lot of the
time. So, yeah, we do want to shout them
out. And and so, yeah, thank y'all for
all that you do. Love y'all. And um
someone mentioned, oh, we want to thank
those of you who took the initiative to
post the 100 days of prayer link in
Mighty Networks. Thank you for that. You
know, we have so much going on at Living
Mana with our own uh programming and we
have some things in the works and some
ideas coming up. It just didn't seem to
be practical for us to stop everything
for 100 days and do the 100 days of
prayer. But if you pray and ask the Lord
how he can use you, you can get the
link. You can download the materials and
say, "Lord, how would you use me to do
this? Maybe I can participate with a
small group in my home as an individual
or maybe in your uh one of your small
group ministries or you can pass it out
to other people." But uh praise God for
that and for everybody who took the time
to post and share as much information as
you can about that. Uh we do appreciate
it. We do appreciate it very much. We
also want to invite you today remember
the afterlow. Sister Jerry will be
hosting the afterlow today and uh we
will look forward to uh her leading us
through. You know I wanted to say
something. Pastor Andante, we're gonna
whenever Amber does the praise reports,
we're gonna come back. I was really
inspired listening to Pastor Andante's
story about remembering some of the
awesome things God had done for them,
you know, and how they were out here in
San Diego with the children and then
they went back home and and and went to
the mailbox and there was that big, you
know what, as I was listening to them
tell that story, I started say, Amber,
come on, let's let's go let's walk out
here to this
mailbox because
Lord, I was inspired by that.
Oh my god. So anyway, praise God.
I wanted to take a walk to the mailbox.
Okay. Well,
praise God. That was a special blessing,
right? Amen. Amen. Okay, sweetheart. All
right. Well, before I get into the
praise
reports and some reminders about emails
that you can uh send out, I just wanted
to share a very important need that we
have. So, we have an amazing prayer
team and we need more people on our
prayer team, especially for special ops
groups. We have a lot of people in need
of daily prayer. Amen. And it doesn't
take special talent to pray. We all can
pray. This is something that everyone
can do. And so, you know, we
really have a need to have more prayer
warriors. Do not don't be intimidated by
the word warrior either. Um, you know,
we have some some amazing people um
really praying for us, but we need more.
We need more prayer warriors. We need
people to step up to the plate and pray
for our Living Mana members. We're even
praying for people outside of the church
um and just wrapping our arms around
them and walking them through their
their their issues, whether it be health
issues, whether it be financial issues,
we have a lot of need. And so, um, if
you would like to join the prayer team,
um, and a special ops prayer team under
the prayer team
umbrella, please send an email to pray
living
manana.urch. That same email can be used
if you have a prayer request for
yourself or a loved one or a praise
report that you would like to share. and
then I will read that on uh a future
Sabbath. So if you have a request for a
special ops team for yourself or a loved
one and we have a lot of requests and
not enough people to pray. So um please
send an email to spec ops that's s
[Music]
ps living
mana.urch. If you would like to join the
women's ministry, please email women
living manana.urch. And finally, if you
would like to join the men's ministry,
please send an email to seven loaves.
That's sen l a
vivingman.
Church. All right, first praise
report. This one was sent to me um from
Sharon Fay Johnson. I also want to
apologize because I read a praise report
that was also sent to me and I
accidentally
um said it was from her and it wasn't.
It was from an anonymous person and so I
apologize for that mixup. Um but Sharon
Fay says, "I've been in the wilderness
running. Something happened that made me
realize it was time for me to come home
to Living Mana Online Church. I realized
that this is a true fate that I did not
absolutely need to walk away from. I'm
so happy. I have not been happy since I
left LOC and I have gained my happiness
in Christ since I have made the decision
to return. Praise God. Hallelujah. Thank
you, Jesus. And the blessed Holy Ghost
spirit truth. Glory. Hallelujah. Come
on, somebody. That's rejoicing right
there. Yes. That's a praise report
from Zagwa Malangu. Thank you prayer
team for praying for me. It went well
and I am now awaiting the final judgment
from the judge. May God bless you all
while awaiting the response. Help me to
thank
God. So praise there from Stacy
Ferguson. Praise report. The animal
sanctuary dryer broke in between
rainstorms in California. We were able
to place the washable pet pads, which
are the majority of the laundry, out on
the fence daily, load after load. Then
we put the dryer pads back in the dryer
with no heat to remove the hair and lint
almost every day for a week so we never
fell behind in the laundry with God's
help. At the end of the week, we were
able to pay a helper to install a used
dryer that needed a few repairs, while a
friend ordered the sanctuary a brand new
dryer, which will arrive in April.
Praise God. Amen. Amen. From Petal.
Hello, Warriors. I'd like to thank you
for your prayers. Monday, May 31st was
officially my last day at my current
employer. Although I considered leaving
Germany, the authorities here are quite
supportive and I intend to do some
further upskilling training over the
next four or five months to be better
positioned to meet changing market
demands. I'm praying for you all, Pastor
Myers and family, brother Terry and
Sister Amoris, Sister Pauline, and the
rest of the team too. God bless you all.
Thank you, Pedal, for your praise
report. And I absolutely love your name,
too. Amen. Amen. From Leon
Riley. Shout out to you guys who prayed
for my mom. She was first referred to
hospice care. Then she was given
rehabilitation, but we took her home to
care for her. With your prayers and
trust in God, we just received the news
that her lungs are healing well.
Hallelujah. Our lungs are clear. We
praise God for his miracles for my mom.
I was actually waiting to hear that she
had passed. Thank you for your prayers.
I have two praise reports from Pauline
Goodine. The first one, Nahima and her
nursing cohorts all passed their final
exams. They are now starting their next
journey to becoming an RN, registered
nurse. Amen. They wanted me to tell the
team that they truly appreciate their
prayers. Hallelujah. And praise report
number two. I want to brag about my God
who came through and protected me and my
family through the tornadoes that
descended on Nashville, Tennessee. Glory
to his mighty name to protect and save.
Hallelujah. Praise his name. And I know
that she was in a in a hospital
concurge or or somewhere in there where
they were all kind of hunkering down
from the the tornadoes. Yeah.
From Shaunene Wright, thank you Jesus
for another day of life. I praise you
for answering my prayers, the prayers of
my sisters and brothers. Thank you for
alleviating my pain in Jesus name. Amen.
Amen. And finally, I caught this uh
praise report in the chat this morning
from Katie S. might sound a bit silly,
but thank you for praying for my mom's
allergies last Sabbath. It was quite bad
prior, but now she's having no symptoms
and she doesn't take meds for it. And
that is not silly at all. No, not at
all. So, we praise God for your mother
feeling better. Allergies are Amen. not
not not a good thing. So, Amen. So,
amen. Praise God. And listen, you know,
um sometimes we could just read over
those praise reports and take Let us not
do that and take it for granted, saints.
God is a good God. He does hear and
answer prayer. And so, uh as as Ammer
said earlier, you know, we do need more
prayer warriors. You know the quote that
sister White said, you know, angels,
mighty angels, awesome angels, awesome
creatures, look at us and they wonder
with the power of prayer why we don't
pray more than we do. And you know, we
ought to pray more saints. We really
are. We hear the saying sometimes, well,
the least I can do is pray for you. No,
that's not the least at all. That's the
most you can do when you truly
understand the power of prayer and how
instrumental it is. is I was sharing
with the prayer warriors u last week and
probably a little bit more the week
before even how Paul told the
Philippians you know we were going
through it he told the sec he told the
Corinthians we were going through it but
you helping together through your
prayers and the supply of the Holy
Spirit God delivered us he does deliver
us and we conf we're con we're we're
confident that he will yet deliver us
but Paul made sure that he put in the
scriptures by the inspiration of the
Holy Spirit the importance of the
prayers of the saints and it's powerful
ful and instrumental in the deliverance.
That's the plan that God has a part of
his plan that for deliverance, for
salvation, for healing and and and and
for the furtherance of the faith of the
saints has been about our prayers. And
so encourage you to keep on praying.
Want to thank all of our living mana
prayer warriors and warettes. Y'all are
something else. We couldn't do what we
do without it without you. And so all of
the ministries, the vision, the purpose
of living mana, everything is covered by
that spiritual air coverage that you
provide when you're on your knees
praying. Want to thank those of you who
are not officially a part of the prayer
ministry team, but we know some of you
are indeed prayer warriors. I know that.
I've talked with you. I fellowship with
you. I've prayed with you. And so, thank
you for continuing to pray. But uh and
they're so selfless going through their
own trials and their own situations. and
they never stop praying for other
people. Yeah, that that's been the theme
lately. That's really been the thing
with brother Elco and sister Angela has
been doing it for some time now going
through their own storms. We had a thing
where every time a new prayer warrior
joined our ranks, storms broke out and
sometimes we were wondering, should we
say anything? We sit back and watch and
sure enough it happened. But God using
those storms made us riders of the
storms, spiritual storms. troopers and
we're going to pray here in a moment.
But God used those to bring us closer to
him, to teach us to trust and rely on
him because some of the same storms that
we went through. We were praying for
people who are going through the same
stuff. So, thank God for his goodness.
And so, today we want to remember to
pray for our pastor and our first lady
and their family. uh the entire LMOC
family, board members, our leaders, all
of our ministries, everything, our our
vision, our sevenfold vision that God
will uh bless living man and hold it up.
And we'll pray in just a second here.
Want to remember to lift up brother Elco
and his family. Elco just lost his
mother. Sister Angela who's in the
hospital. We're praying that the Lord
deliver our beloved sister to us uh
shortly. Want to pray for all of the
special ops teams uh prayer teams and
all of our LMOC warriors. Whether you're
on a special ops team or not, we're
praying for them. Want to remember
sister Ashley Owens who needs and as
soon as possible she needs an MRI and an
EEG. She's been going through a series
of uh having seizures and even losing
consciousness and she wants to get to
the bottom of that. So Ashley, we're
praying for you urgently, most urgently.
Uh again, uh we want to remember Margot
Begley. She's asking for healing for
Gloria. Uh spiritual insight and
conviction for Robert. Uh Laya is asking
that we keep her and Wes in our prayers
that Wes would be approved for his
rheumatoid arthritis medication that
that would be paid for and be taken care
of. And as you know, Sister Laya and
brother Wes are have been praying uh
earnestly to move to Idaho. uh sister
Katie who we just uh thank God for her
her mother's allergies being relieved
last week as we prayed for her. But
we're also asking the God to bless her
and touch her that her thyroid would
shrink so she wouldn't have to have
surgery. Sister Esther White is asking
that we continue to pray for her
recovery from surgery. Praise God for
you, Sister Esther. We will. Sister
Anetta Carr has been having uh severe
respiratory issues and wants us to keep
her in our prayers. We will do that. Uh
want to pray for all the tornadoes in
the south. everybody that's been
affected by those. Um, I want to
remember to pray. Alexander Sonatada
Santana just gave us a prayer request
via email asking for deliverance over
self, world, and the enemy. And he's
praying that his children will want to
follow Jesus. We're praying for Tanya,
for Mitchell, uh, for Connor, for Corey,
for Na, Nico, uh, Sahara, Karina, and
Shane. So, praise God. Hallelujah. Nurse
Sandy is asking that we would pray for
Haiti. Her old neighborhood has been
overrun by gangs and the gangs has have
literally run people from their homes.
And so these people are now homeless.
And so we are praying Lord in the name
of Jesus. Swoop down through that
neighborhood with those angels and drive
them out. May they hear uh the rushing
of a mighty wind through that
neighborhood and run those gangs folks
out of there. And um it's spiritual is
asking. She says that she's living a
Job's life, physical, mental, spiritual,
and financial. She says she's never been
rich nor righteous like Job, but she
believes she's in a many Job situation.
We a lot of us know what that's like,
sister. Uh and so we're definitely
praying for you. It is spirit. It's
spiritual. Uh and that could you could
be a brother or a sister. I don't I'm
not sure, but uh do excuse me, but we
will be praying. Whoever you are, we're
praying. Um we also want to pray for Mr.
Sneaky has started attending a new 7th
Day Adventist church and he feels like
God is calling him to lead out there,
but he wants to do that in the right
spirit. And so, brother, we're praying
for you that God will lead you and guide
you uh in that new SDA church that
you're in. We need it. Brother Tom and
Joyce Fiser, SH sister Joyce just was
released from the hospital on Wednesday.
She had an intestinal blockage. So,
we'll be praying for her strengthening
and recovery. Tom and Joyce, we love
y'all. Thank y'all for all the work that
you do. we have not forgotten about the
homeless ministry that you've been
involved in. We're definitely praying
that. Um, Sister Vivian Shelton has
asked Shelton is asking that we pray for
her daughter Sabrina Quinn. Uh, she's
going through a series of storms in her
life and some anxiety and stuff there.
So, we're we're praying that God bring
her on through. Um, um, Sister Gigi has
asked that we would pray for the health
of April Allen. Uh uh we do know sister
Allan and we thank you uh for for
sharing that with us. Sister Gi, we will
definitely be keeping her in prayer.
We're praying for brother Dron Jones uh
that the Lord will just surround his
life with his goodness. We're going to
pray for the puppy Judah. Uh I knew
you'd still have that dog by now, Gigi.
So, praise God that uh the Lord will uh
bless the dog and bring healing. Praying
for the graphics and communication team.
Each of them have been going through
some storms. just going through saints
and the rest of the prayer requests that
you may have put in the chat if I did
not get them or one came through or
there maybe there's some unspoken prayer
requests in that chat. Listen saints,
our God is big enough, big enough to
cover it all. And he is amazing miracle
working God. He's the same yesterday,
today, and forever. He's the rose of
Sharon, the lily of the valley, the
bright and morning star, the lion of the
tribe of Judah. He's a friend that
stickketh closer than a brother. He's a
rock in a weary land. Water when you're
thirsty. Bread when you're hungry. He
will comfort you when you're going
through it in your heart and mind. Let
us give him praise and glory in this
place today. Father, in the name of
Jesus, hallelujah. God, we lift you up.
You have heard these prayer requests.
You have heard the needs of your people
and all that they are going through.
Lord, we know that not only do you have
the answer, but you are the answer.
Amen. Come, Lord Jesus, and fill our
hearts today. Forgive us for the sins
that we have committed against you in
word and thought and deed. Things we
should have done and did not do. Things
we know we shouldn't have done and done
in any way. Lord, have mercy on us in
our weakness and infirmities. Come and
wash us, cleanse us as we confess our
sins and send them forth to judgment.
Lord, Lord Jesus, blot out our sins from
the record of heaven. We pray in your
glorious and wonderful name today, God,
that we might stand in communion and
fellowship with you, Lord. that we might
walk in the light as you're in the light
and that the blood, the precious blood
of Jesus would cleanse us from all
unrighteousness and sin today. Lord,
we're not asking just that you would
forgive us of our sins, but we're
asking, oh God, that you would continue
to cleanse us and wash us, purge us with
hissip that we might be clean. Wash us,
oh God, that we might be whiter than
snow. And thank you, Lord, having heard
our confession today. Lord, you're also
hearing our prayers on behalf of
ourselves and others who are in need.
Thank you, Lord, that you are Jehovah
Gyra. Thank you that you are the alpha
and the omega. Oh God, you're the same
yesterday and today and forever. Oh God,
you know the ending before the beginning
even begins. Give us a new perspective,
oh Lord, of these storms and trials that
we're going through. Help us in this
memory training that we would look back
and remember how faithful you were not
only in our lives but in the lives of
others Lord God who you've left us the
sacred record to read and you've left us
these praise reports to see how you have
brought us through. You're no respector
of persons. Hallelujah. What you've done
for one, you will do for another. I
don't know anybody less deserving than
me. But God look at the grace and mercy
and the goodness you've shown in my
life. Oh God, chief of sinners. Oh Lord,
as far as I can see, as far as I know,
and you had mercy. Came all the way
down, hallelujah, to a prison cell, Lord
God, where I was surrounded by
oppression and darkness, chaos and
madness. Men who had resolved to live
the rest of their lives in prison, in
darkness, hurting and hurting one
another. Lord, in Jesus' name, you can
save from the guttermost to the
uttermost. Heal, touch, and deliver.
Someone listening today may be at their
wits end. Someone don't see an answer.
Someone don't see a way out. Stretch
forth thy mighty hand and do miracles,
signs, and wonders today. Lord, in the
name of thy holy child Jesus, relieve
the oppressed, Lord. Set the captive
free. Provide for those in need in Jesus
mighty name. God, miraculously come
through. Somebody need to take a walk to
that mailbox today and open it up and
find that check in there. Just the
amount they need, oh Lord God. And if
it's more, may they take and give to
somebody else in need. In Jesus' name,
you are able to provide just as you
brought a coin out of a fish's mouth for
your servant to pay taxes. You still
work miracles for gold and silver are
all yours, Lord. Cattle on a thousand
hill. It's yours, Lord. The earth is the
Lord's and the fullness thereof. We lift
you up and we magnify you today in Jesus
name. Lord, we cast down our doubt, our
unbelief, and our fear and our anxiety,
our our anger, our bad attitudes,
everything that has plagued us and stood
between us and your perfect will for our
lives. We cast it down today and we give
you all of the glory. Hallelujah. We
give you all of the honor and praise
because you are worthy. And thank you,
God, for being mindful of us. We thank
you for hearing these prayers today and
answering these prayers. And now, oh
God, with the peace of God beginning to
flood our soul even in this very moment,
flooding our heart and mind as we think
about the goodness of God. Hallelujah.
We're now ready to hear your word today.
Thank you for our our pastor. Thank you
for your servant who has consistently
and faithfully, Lord God, uh stretched
forth his hand to take hold of the hand
of omnipotence in order that he might
feed your sheep. Thank you for this
faithful shepherd, Lord, in Jesus name
that you have brought to Living Man a
church. Lord, we pray as we are as he's
bringing this word and breaking the
bread of life today that our hearts
would be attentive that our minds would
be alert that our feet would be shaw
with the preparation of the gospel of
peace that we not only hear it we not
only believe it but we walk it out we
obey it in Jesus mighty and glorious
name father and so Lord we just thank
you we praise you we bless you today on
your Sabbath in Jesus name and all God's
peoples declare amen
[Music]
Amen. You are
here moving in our midst.
I worship
you. I worship
you. You are
here working in this
place. I worship
you. I worship you.
You are
here touching every
heart. I worship
you. I worship
you. You are
here healing every
heart. I worship
you. I worship you.
Cuz you are way maker, miracle worker,
promise keeper, light in the darkness.
My God, that is who you
are. Oh, you are way maker, miracle
worker, promise keeper, light in the
darkness. My God, that is who you are.
You are
here turning lives
around. I worship
you. I worship
you. You are
here men in every
heart. I worship
you. I worship you.
Oh, you are way maker, miracle worker,
promise keeper, light in the darkness.
My God, that is who you
are. Oh, you are way maker, miracle
worker, promise keeper, light in the
darkness. My God, that is who you
are. That is who you
[Music]
are. Even when I don't see it, you're
working. Even when I don't feel it,
you're working. You never stop. You
never stop working. You never stop. You
never stop working. Even when I don't
see it, you're working. Even when I
don't feel it, you're working. You never
stop. You never stop working. You never
stop. You never stop working. Even when
I don't see it, you're working. Even
when I don't feel it, you're working.
You never stop. You never stop working.
Even when I don't see you working. Even
when I don't feel it, you're working.
You never stop. You never stop working.
You never
stop. Cuz you are way maker, miracle
worker, promise keeper, light in the
darkness. My God, that is who you
are. Oh, you are way maker, miracle
worker, promise keeper, light in the
darkness. My God, that is who you are.
That is who you
are. That is who you are.
That is who you are.
That is who you
are. Sing wide, all ye
heavens. Let the praise go up as the
walls come down. All
creation, everything with breath. Repeat
the sound. All his
children clean and pure
[Music]
[Applause]
hearts. Oh Lord my God.
When I in awesome
wonder consider all the works thy hand
hath
made. I see the
stars. I hear the mighty
thunder. Thy power
throughout the universe displayed.
Then sings my soul, my Savior cry to
thee. How great thou
are. How great
thou and sings my soul, my savior God to
me. How great thou art. How great thou
are.
And when I think that God his son not
sparing sent him to die, I scarce can
take it
in. That on the
cross my burden gladly
bearing. He
bend to take away my sin.
This is my soul, my
savior.
You
[Music]
th my soul, my savior.
[Applause]
[Music]
I when Christ shall come with shout of
acclamation.
[Music]
ation and take me home. What joy shall
fill my
heart then shall I
bow in humble
adoration and they
proclaim my God how great thou
art until that
day when heaven builds us
welcome and as we walk this welcome Come
for
reward. Your kingdom
come. Deliver us from
evil and
will our God how great you
are. We hope we
sing. Our God.
[Applause]
He sings my song, my savior God to
me. How great
are great.
[Music]
This sings my song, my Savior God
toe. How great
[Music]
thou. Amen. church family. I want to
welcome everyone to uh living mana once
again. Uh we are getting ready to uh get
into part nine of the nine essentials
for the time of trouble
series. And
uh today I believe God has something
very powerful, many things powerful to
say to us. And so we're going to go
ahead and jump right in. And let me just
say real quick, I was not able to hear
that intro just now, but it looked
really, really, really good. So, I'm
looking forward to going back and
listening to that intro um once this is
over. Um, but we're going to be talking
about temperance today. So, go ahead and
put that one in the chat if you are
ready to get into the word of God. And,
um, we're going to go ahead and and
pray. Let's do that now. Heavenly
Father, um before we get into this
message, Lord, I want to lift up faith
uh who has just mentioned in the chat
that today is a difficult day for her.
It is the
um I believe it would have been their
15th year anniversary, her husband and
her, but he's passed. And Lord, today is
a difficult day for her, Lord. And so I
just lift her up. I lift up her
children.
Um, and Lord,
um, I just ask that your presence would
be with them. Just keep them. Just watch
over them,
Lord. And today, Lord, we're praying
that you would speak a word to us. Lord,
you've given me a whole lot and I'm I'm
asking you that you would help me to
make this message
clear that you would speak through me,
Lord, and that you would speak that your
people may hear and receive it. So Lord,
bless us now as we as we get ready to
eat. Bless this meal, Lord. Bless this
mana today is our prayer in Jesus name.
Amen.
Um, all
right. Let's go ahead, guys, and uh and
jump in. I see the ones in the chat. Uh,
we're going to go ahead and go to our
very first
slide. Uh, Daniel 12 and verse one.
Daniel 12 and verse one. The Bible says,
"And at that time shall Michael stand up
the great prince which standeth for the
children of thy people. And there shall
be a time of trouble such as never was
since there was a nation, even to that
same time. And at that time thy people
shall be delivered, everyone that shall
be found written in the book." We're
told in the book of
Daniel that a time of trouble is coming,
a time unlike any other time in this
world's history. And the only ones that
will be protected in that time of
trouble are those who are described in
Revelation 7 11. Note with me,
Revelation 71, I'm sorry, Revelation
7:1. Uh the Bible says, "And after these
things, I saw four angels standing on
the four corners of the earth, holding
the four winds of the earth, that the
wind should not blow on the earth, nor
on the sea, nor on any
tree." And I saw another angel ascending
from the east, having the seal of the
living God. And he cried with a loud
voice to the four angels to whom it was
given to hurt the earth and the sea,
saying, "Hurt not the earth, nor the
sea, nor the trees, till we have sealed
the servants of our God in their
foreheads." We understand that the seal
of God is the work of the Holy Spirit
who is the sealer. The Bible tells us,
"Grieve not the Holy Spirit of God,
whereby you are sealed unto the day of
redemption." The Holy Spirit is the
sealer, and the Holy Spirit is sealing
us with his character. In Galatians
chapter 5 22 and 23, the Bible says,
"But the fruit of the spirit is love,
joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness,
goodness, faith, meekness, and
temperance. Against such there is no
law." Against such there is no law. We
have spent uh the last nine messages or
last eight messages uh on each one of
these fruit temperance I'm sorry uh love
joy peace longsuffering gentleness
goodness faith meekness and today we are
dealing with temperance what does
temperance mean in the time of trouble
our
love our joy our peace our longsuffering
our gentle
our faith, our meekness, and our
temperance is going to be
tested. They are each going to be
tested. Therefore, it is crucial that we
understand what these fruit mean and how
they are manifested in the life of the
believer. So, what is temperance?
Temperance is self-control. Put that in
the chat for me, please. Temperance is
self-ontrol.
self-control. So what we can understand
from this is that our selfont
control will be tested. Now
self-control actually kind of simplifies
or makes
this this understanding of
temperance
simpler than it actually is.
And we want to get deeper into this
understanding of self-control because I
think when we get deeper into this thing
of self-control, we're going to see
things that we may not have seen before.
And so what I'm going to present to you
today is that there are two
sides to
intemperance or there are two sides to
this question of temperance.
Side A is in tempmperence in sin. So
y'all go ahead and put that in the chat.
In tempmperence in sin. That is side A
of the issue. Side B of the issue is
temperance in
righteousness. Temperance in
righteousness. So A temperance in sin. B
I'm sorry. A inmperence in sin. be
temperance in
righteousness. Temperance in
righteousness. And we're going to look
at these two sides of the question of
temperance in order to better
understand what we mean when we say
self-control. What we mean when we're
talking about the fruit of the spirit
being temperance.
So I want to suggest to you that the
very first sin or the cause of the very
first
sin in the Bible is in
tempmperance. The cause of the very
first sin in the Bible or in fact the
very first sin in the Bible in the book
of Genesis in the garden of Eden was the
sin of tempmpance. Let's go to the
screen and I want you to note with me
Galatians chapter 3. I'm sorry. Uh,
Genesis chapter 3. Genesis chapter 3,
beginning with verse 1. The Bible says,
"Now, the serpent was more subtle than
any beast of the field which the Lord
God had made. And he said unto the
woman, Ya, has God said, Ye shall not
eat of every tree of the garden." And
the woman said unto the serpent, "We may
eat of the fruit of the trees of the
garden, but of the fruit of the tree
which is in the midst of the garden. God
has said, you shall not eat of it,
neither shall you touch it, lest you
die." And the serpent said unto the
woman, "You uh you shall not surely die,
for God does know that in a day you eat
thereof, then your eyes shall be opened,
and you shall be as gods, knowing good
and evil.
And when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food, and that it was pleasant
to the eyes, and a tree to be desired to
make one wise, she took of the fruit
thereof, and did eat, and gave also unto
her husband with her, and he did eat,
and the eyes of them both were opened.
And they knew that they were naked, and
they sewed fig leaves together, and made
themselves aprons.
Now, what what's going on here? Why are
we pointing to to this uh this
event and connecting in temperance with
it? I want you to know this. Prior to
Eve's
fall, her
thought was of the
future. The word of God, God himself has
told me how to live.
He has told me how I should uh the
things that I should do. He has he has
instructed
us
and Adam and Eve's only
desire was to live out the future that
God had in store for them. So y'all put
a one in the chat if that makes sense to
you. Their only concern, their only
desire was to live out the future that
God had for them. All things are going
to be good. By the way, just don't do
this. But if you do this, everything is
going to be
good. After her discussion with the
serpent, the
present now bea now began to carry more
weight or now carried more weight than
the
future. All right, y'all put a two in
chat if you follow what I just
said. Before Adam, before her discussion
with the
serpent, they were only concerned with
the the the the picture that God had
painted for them. This is your future.
Go ahead and live that
out. But Satan comes
along and he offers her
something
present. He's offering her something in
the now.
Come on, let's break this
down. I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm gonna give
you a statement and we're going to work
off of this statement. In
tempmperance is when the desire for now
exceeds the desire for the
future. All right, we're going to be
doing a lot of numbers today, so I want
you to put a five in the chat if that
made sense to you. And temperance is
when the desire for
now exceeds the desire for the
future. Come
on. In tempmperance is based off of
four faulty premises. And we're going to
see each of these in what happened with
Eve. So number one is urgency. Number
two is fear. Number three is pleasure
and number four is
self-preservation. These are the four
things that inerence is based upon. A
sense of urgency, a sense of
now, there is fear, there is pleasure,
and there is self-preservation. So for
example,
urgency. Satan proposes to Eve that in
the day that she eats this tree,
everything's going to change for her. In
other words, the sooner she eats from
this tree, the better things are going
to be for her. You got to do this now,
Eve. You can't wait. Do this now.
What I want you to understand, beloved,
is that in
tempmperance
typically
leads to taking
actions
now that are going to jeopardize your
future. Am I making sense?
So number one, Eve, if you don't in the
day you eat thereof, the sooner you eat
of this, you're going to be better
off. There's a there's a sense of
urgency. You got to eat from this now,
Eve. Don't wait. Eat from this now.
Number two, fear.
Fear, Eve. God is holding out. God is
holding something back from you.
Something that is causing you to miss
out. To miss out. Let me ask something.
How many of you have ever have ever
exercised in
temperance in how you
eat? I'm just going to give you a a a
very simple but powerful example. An
inmperance in how you eat. Like you know
you shouldn't eat it,
but the temporary
pleasure you're going to get from it.
You don't want to miss
out. Anybody ever had that experience?
I'mma eat this man cuz I don't want to
miss out. I'm afraid of passing this up
because I will miss
out. Which leads to number three,
pleasure. So, there's a sense of
urgency. Satan's going to tell you, "Do
this thing now." There's a sense of
fear, you might miss out. There's a
there's there's the offer of pleasure.
So note how in the text it actually says
when she saw that the tree was uh was
pleasant to the
eyes. Pleasant to the
eyes, a tree that was
desirable. And temperance is often
wrapped up in a
desire. There's an urgency. Do this
thing now. There's fear. I might miss
out. There's pleasure. Man, this going
to this going to be good. And then
there's
self-preservation. This is going to make
me feel better. This is going to make me
uh h this going to make me
happy. This is going to make me happy.
So those are the four things. Urgency,
fear, pleasure, and self-preservation.
Are y'all with me so far? I want you I
want to show you this in another
example. Let's go to the book of Genesis
chapter 25, and we're going to read
verse 29 and 30. Notice what the Bible
says here, speaking about a man by the
name of Esau. The Bible says, "And Jacob
saw pottage. And Esau came from the
field and was faint. And Esau said to
Jacob, "Feed me, I pray thee, with that
same red pottage, for I am faint."
Therefore, his name was called Edom.
Reading on, "And Jacob said, Sell me
this day thy birthright." And Esau said,
"Behold, I am at the point to
die, and what profit shall this
birthright do to me?" And Jacob said,
"Swear to me this day." And he swore
unto him. And he sold his birthright
unto Jacob. Then Jacob gave Esau bread
and pottage of lentils, and he did eat
and drink, and rose up, and went his
way. Thus Esau despised his birthright.
All right.
We're going to track the same four
principles here. Number one,
urgency. Did Esau have this sense of
urgency in the story? Yes or
no? Was there a sense of urgency? I am
about to faint. And if I don't do this
now, we're going to save that last point
for later because that comes under point
four. But there is a sense of
urgency. Is there fear? Yes. Behold, I
am to the point. I am at the point to
die. And what shall this birthright do
to me? Are y'all
following?
Pleasure. So urgency right there. Fear
right there. Pleasure. Feed me. I pray
thee with that same red pottage. Man, I
want to feel good right now. Feed me.
what you're making smells
good. That's going to be
pleasurable. And then self-preservation.
I'm at the point to die. What is it
going to profit me? This birth right?
I'm going to
die. If I eat this, I will feel
better. And so what does Esau do? Listen
to me, y'all. He
trades away his
future for the
present. Do y'all catch it
now? In
tempmperance is the trading away of your
future for the
present. It's like trading down. What
does that mean trading down? Trading
down is trading something of a higher
value for a lesser value. Are y'all with
me? Esau traded
down. Temper in temperance is the act of
trading
down of of
of giving up something of the
future for the present.
is foolish trading,
y'all. It's a kind of trading that makes
you go like, "Wait, what?" It's the
trading that reveals, listen to me now,
it's the trading that reveals that while
you profess to believe in eternal life,
you're actually more into the principle
of
yolo. Anybody know what yolo
is? What is that? Y O L O. What does
that principle represent? What what does
that uh uh acronym represent?
YOLO. Let's
see.
You
only live
once. That's right.
And temperance is the
exposing or the
revealing of an attitude of yolo. I only
live once. I better do this or else I'm
going to miss
out. A and
yeah, I'm trading
down. But but here it's like Luke 12:19
says, you'll see it on the screen. I
would say to my soul, soul, thou has
much goods laid up for many years. Take
thine knees, eat, drink,
and be
merry. Like enjoy life now. You only
live once. You only live once. This
idea, this understanding of
inmperance is basically trading
righteousness for
sin. Are are y'all following what I'm
saying? You're
trading, it's almost as if you're
liquidating your future blessings for
present temporal satisfaction.
You're just liquidating your blessings
because it's a
trade. In tempmperance is a trade. Every
time an inmperant act is made, it's a
trade. It's saying, "Hey, I'd rather
live for the present than for the
future. I'd rather live for present sin
than for future righteousness and future
promises and future glory." Come on, let
let me give you one more example. Let's
go to 2 Samuel 11:2. 2 Samuel 11:2 the
Bible says, "And it came to pass at
evening tide that David arose from off
his bed and walked upon the roof of the
king's house. And from the roof he saw a
woman washing herself, and the woman was
very beautiful to look
upon." And David sent and inquired after
the woman, and one said, "Is not this
Basheba, the daughter of Eliam, the wife
of Uriah the Hitittite?" And David sent
messengers and took her, and she came in
unto him, and he lay with her, for she
was purified from her uncleanness, and
she returned unto her house. I want to
see if you can see the four
premises of inmperance. Was David in
tempmperate
here? The answer is absolutely yes, he
was. Was there an urgency? I gotta have
this now. I have to have her now. That's
what inance is. It is I've got to have
it and I gotta have it now. Fear. If I
don't have her now, I might miss out on
her. I might miss out on this thing
forever. So, I better do this now for
fear that something is being withheld
from
me. Was there pleasure?
Yeah, the text literally says that she
was pleasant to his eyes. She was
beautiful to look upon,
urgency,
fear, pleasure, and then and then
self-preservation. I will be happier if
I get her. I will be
satisfied. Are y'all following me?
These four premises, urgency, fear, huh
uh pleasure, and
self-preservation are the basis of
inmperence. Now, let me ask you a
question. When you exercise intemperance
in something, you're addicted to
something, do you sense those four
things?
urgency. Gotta do this
now. I don't have the I can't help
myself. Got to do this now. Fear of
missing out. If I don't do this, I might
suffer. Pleasure. If I do this, it's
going to feel real good even though I
know it's wrong. Self-preservation. If I
do this, it will make me feel happy.
These are the things of inmperence. This
is this is what
Satan comes and offers every time he's
offering an intemperate
act.
Um, I want you to note what's happening
when I said in tempmperance is a trade.
I want you to see what I'm talking
about. Come with me to 1 Corinthians
chapter 6 20. 1 Corinthians chapter 6
verse 20. And look at what the Bible
says here. The Bible says, "For you are
brought bought with a price. Therefore,
glorify God in your body and in your
spirit which are God." So, let me ask
you a question. Does the Bible say that
we are bought with a
price? Absolutely. Absolutely. We are
bought with a price. That means God has
purchased us. Jesus has purchased us.
And I want you to notice what he
purchased us with. In Acts 20:8 28, it
says, "Take heed thereof unto yourselves
and and to all the flock over the which
the Holy Ghost has made you overseers to
feed the church of God, which he has
purchased with his own
blood. We have been purchased with the
blood of
Jesus." And in that purchase, watch
this. In that purchase, according to
Romans 6:23, the Bible says, "For the
wages of sin is death, but the gift of
God is eternal life through Jesus Christ
our Lord." So in our being
purchased by the blood of the lamb, he
also purchased our
future. He purchased our He purchased
eternal life for us. He's purchased our
future. So here's what happens, beloved.
In
temperance is when we take what Jesus
has purchased for us and we say hm
birthright versus present pleasure. I
think I'mma go
ahead and sell the
birthright for present pleasure.
Just like
Esau, just like
David, just like
Eve.
Therefore, every intemperate act is you
saying present sin is worth more to me
than the future investment of God, than
the future promises of God.
In temperance is trading
down. Whereas we should be trading
up. Trading up is when you're trading
something of lesser value for something
of greater
value. In
tempmperance is doing business with
Satan.
How H how how is that? How's that
sound? And
temperance is is a business transaction.
Hey, Satan says, "Hey, listen. Um you
give me your
future." You know what's crazy? As I was
reading that story of uh of uh Jacob and
Esau, Jacob did something wrong. God
never told Jacob, you know, try to get
the birth right this way. He did
something wrong. But in that which he
did
wrong, that is an exact
picture of what the devil wants to do
with
us. Hey, what will you give me for the
birthright? What will me what will you
give me for your
future? It is making a deal with the
devil. So So watch this. Now we can
understand in Matthew 4:1. Now we can
understand this. Let's go ahead and read
this. Then then was Jesus led up of the
spirit into the wilderness to be tempted
of the devil. And when he had fasted 40
days and 40 nights, he was afterward
hungered. And when the tempter came to
him, he said, "If thou be the son of
God, command that these stones be made
bread." But he answered and said, "It is
written, man shall not live by bread
alone, but by every word that proceedth
out of the mouth of God." Now let me ask
you a
question. Was there urgency
here? Was there urgency
here? Jesus, you're hungry and you're
hungry now. You've been hungry for 40
days. Was there a sense of
urgency? Was there a sense or or let me
ask it this way. Was Satan trying to
trying to put upon Jesus a sense of
urgency? Was he trying to put upon Jesus
a sense of fear? If you don't eat now,
you'll suffer
longer. I'm trying to help you out here.
If you don't eat now, you'll suffer
longer. By the way, if you turn this
stone to bread, man, wouldn't that be
pleasant? Wouldn't that be
pleasant? Wouldn't that be so
pleasurable? M think about that warm
bread just just crumbling in your mouth
right now and then just filling your
stomach. And by the way,
self-preservation, you'll feel better.
It'll make you happier. Satan came to
Jesus with these four underlying
premises. A a a sense of urgency. Man,
you've been hungry for 40 days. Fear if
you don't eat. By the way, not only if
you don't eat, but really, are you the
son of God? Are you
sure, man? You know what? If you really
are, then you should have power to turn
the stone to bread. Aren't you afraid
that you're not the son of God? You know
what? Hey, why don't you go ahead and do
this? A sense of urgency, a sense of
fear, pleasure. Hey, this bread is going
to make it's going to satisfy your
hunger, self-preservation. You will feel
better. But let me show you how Jesus
responds and how we should respond to
each one of these four false premises.
Come on y'all. Psalm
37:9. For the evildoers shall be cut
off, but those that wait upon the
Lord, they shall inherit the
earth. When the devil comes with a sense
of urgency, you got to do this now. You
got to have this now. You say, "Nah,
I'll wait." That's what temperance is.
Temperance is saying, "I'll wait." The
devil says, "No, you got to do this now.
You got to get into this relationship
now. You got to have this thing now. You
got to get this thing
now." And it's often those intemperate
actions that get us into the trouble
that we get ourselves into. When the
devil comes and says, "Urgency, you got
to do it now." You respond with now.
I'll wait. I'll wait. Why am I waiting?
because I know that something better is
coming in the future. Are y'all with me?
The reason we wait on the
Lord is because we know that what is in
the future is better than anything Satan
can offer in the
present. When he comes with the sense of
fear, remember this verse, there is no
fear in love. 1 John 4:18, there is no
fear in love, but perfect love cast out
fear because fear has torment. He that
fearth is not made perfect in love. So
when the devil comes with a sense of
urgency, you say, "Nah, I'm not in a
rush. I'll wait." When the devil comes
with a sense of fear, man, you're going
to miss out. Hey, perfect love. Perfect
love for God. Perfect love for his word
cast out that fear that you're going to
miss out on something in the present.
Are y'all with
me? Psalm 84:11. Psalm 84:11. The Lord,
for the Lord God is a son and a shield.
The Lord will give grace and glory. No
good thing will he withhold from them
that walk uprightly. So you got to know
when the devil says, "Hey, aren't you
afraid of missing out? Missing out on
this party? Missing out on this drug?
Missing out on this thing? Missing out
on this girl? Missing out on this guy?"
Remember this. The Bible says, "No good
thing will God
withhold, especially for those that wait
on
him." When the devil says, "Man, look
how pleasant this is." Imagine how
pleasant this will be if you just do
this thing right now. Always remember
this text, y'all. 1 Corinthians chapter
2:9. When the devil tries to get your
eyes to focus on the pleasure of this
world, remember this. As it is written,
"Eye has not seen nor ear heard, neither
has entered into the heart of man the
things which God has prepared for them
that love him." Are y'all with me?
Remember that. Let me show you how this
same verse, so Paul is quoting from the
Old Testament in this verse. But let me
show you how the Old Testament verse
says it. Let's go. Isaiah 64:4. For
since the beginning of the world, men
have not heard, nor perceived by ear,
neither hast the eyes seen, oh God,
beside thee, what he has prepared for
them
that waitth for him.
Ah, do y'all catch
this? The devil is saying now, now, now.
You got to have this
now. But they that wait upon the
Lord. They that wait upon the Lord,
y'all.
Temperance. They that wait upon the
Lord. When the devil comes and says,
"Hey, it's urgent. Hey, aren't you
afraid you're gonna miss out? Hey, uh uh
what about the pleasure? And then when
he comes with that last one,
self-preservation, you will be happy if
you do this. Always remember, beloved,
always remember James 5:11, which says
this, "Behold, we count them happy which
endure." You have heard of the patience
of the of Jo of patience of Job and have
seen the end of the Lord, that the Lord
is very pitiful and of tender mercy.
Listen to me, y'all.
happy. True happiness comes to those
that endure. True happiness comes to
those that wait upon the Lord. We can
see, listen y'all, we can see it again.
When the devil comes back and tempts
Jesus the third time, Matthew 4:9, I
want you to note what the Bible says. It
says again the devil took him up into a
exceeding high mountain and showed him
all the kingdoms of the world and the
glory of them and said unto him all
these things will I give you if you will
fall down and worship me. Now do y'all
see what what the devil's doing
here? Let me show you what the devil's
doing here. He's offering Jesus the
world and he's offering him the world
now.
Do y'all catch that? He's offering Jesus
the world.
Now, Jesus has a picture of the world in
this way. Notice with me, Revelation
21:1, where the Bible says, "And I saw a
new heaven and a new earth, for the
first heaven and the first earth were
passed away, and there was no more sea."
H the devil was offering
Jesus the world now a ruined
world. A world that is going to pass
away and
perish. Satan was like, "Hey, you can
take this now." Jesus said, "Nah, I'm
waiting for the long-term investment.
I'm going to get this world in a
different
state. So Jesus was locked on the future
version while the devil was trying to
get him to focus on the present
version. Are y'all understanding what
I'm saying?
So the devil will come to
you and he will try to offer you the
world now as it is the glories of the
world
now. But beloved like
Jesus we ought to say
no I'll wait I'll wait because something
better is coming. Temperance then is the
refusal to do business with Satan. The
refusal to trade the future blessings
which have already been paid for to buy
death
now. That's what inance is
y'all. It is the refusal to do business
with Satan. Temper. Temp temperance is
long-term
investing while inmperance is
splurging. I want to splurge
now. Let me get everything I can now.
Let me live for the
now. And you end up living in
tempmperately. You end up living life
intemperately.
you end up doing all that you do
inately because you're living for the
now instead of living for the future.
But Paul says, Paul says in 2
Corinthians chapter 4:17, "For our light
affliction, which is but for a moment,
works for us a far more exceeding and
eternal weight and glory."
Beloved, that which is
eternal far
exceeds what the devil has to offer to
us.
Now, we can say it this way. Temperance
is not merely a moral practice, but it
is a prophetic act of
faith. It's you denying the present
because you believe in the future.
Y'all
good? It is
denying present sinful pleasure pleasure
because you
believe in the promises that God has
made for your
future. Temperance.
The Christian has
invested in in a property that is worth
millions. No, no, that is worth
billions. No, no, no, no, no. The
Christian has invested in a future
property that is worth trillions and tr
No, no, no, no. The Christian has
invested in a future property, land,
real estate.
that you cannot put a
number on the value of
it. Why in the world would we trade
down? Why in the world would we would we
trade that which is
eternal for that which
is temporary?
Temperance is deferring sinful
gratification because you believe in the
compound glory of
God. Are y'all catching this? Now
remember guys, this is just side A of
the of the question of
temperance. But I want you to see
beloved that temperance inmperence is a
trait. Intemperance is says this is all
there is. You only live
once. And you can say that while
claiming to be a
Christian. Temperance is refusing to
sell what you
have. It's refusing to do what Esau
did. Are y'all with me? Let's look at
Daniel. Let's talk about Daniel for a
moment.
So, so you remember that in the book of
Daniel, Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego,
they refused to bow
down to the image that is that is set up
before
them. Now, watch this, y'all. Is there
going to be an end time image according
to the book of
Revelation? Yes, there is. Yes, there
is. And I want you to note the
actions. I want you to note the actions
of the three Hebrews. Number one, is
there a sense of urgency? Bow down
now. If you don't bow down now,
something bad is going to happen to you.
There's a sense of urgency. There's a
sense of fear, a fiery
furnace. There's even a sense of
pleasure because the command is not just
to bow down. The command is to bow down
and worship. Enjoy this. Enjoy the
experience. I don't want you to just bow
down. I want you to bow and worship. Be
into it. Feel
it. It's a good
thing. And then self-preservation. If
you don't do this, you're going to
die. If you don't do this, you're going
to die.
And so what is their
response in their the response to the
sense of urgency? Bow down now to my
kingdom. They're like, "No, we've seen
the future kingdom. We are the ones that
told you that there's a stone coming
that is cut out without hands. Why would
we bow to you?" No, no, no, no, no.
We're not bowing to your kingdom now.
There's a kingdom that we will bow to in
the future. So, no thanks. We don't want
to do business with
Babylon. We're we're not tra we're not
doing we're not doing this. We're not
gonna we're not interacting. We're not
trading our future for this present
threat. What about the fear the fiery
furnace? Remember what they said? These
three Hebrews said, "Our God is able to
deliver us and if he
doesn't, we're still not bowing
down." The devil couldn't get them on
urgency. The devil couldn't get them on
fear. What about
pleasure? Yeah, I'm telling you, man.
Worship the image. It'll be good for
you. It will feel good. And you know
what they said? No, no, no. You don't
understand. Eye has not seen nor has ear
heard the things which God has prepared
for them that love him. Beloved, listen
to me. everything that they that they
that was going on in within them to
withstand trading with
Satan. Even down to number four,
self-preservation.
Self-preservation. They love not their
lives until the death. They were willing
to give up their lives. Beloved, if we
want to be temperate in all things, if
we want to have that fruit of
temperance, you cannot do business with
the
devil. You cannot do business with
Babylon. All right. So, yes, Gigi, I'm
sorry. I'm not allowed to buy or
sell. That's what And that's what
temperance is. Temperance is sorry.
Can't give up my birthright for this
thing. Can't give up my birthright for
that thing. Not allowed to buy and sell.
I'm coming back to that. We're coming
back to
that. Y'all good? Okay. Part B. Part B.
Temperate in righteousness. So remember
we said there are two sides of this
questions of temp of this question of
temperance. Number one, there is
intemperance in sin, but there is also
temperance in righteousness. Now,
temperance in righteousness may
initially sound to you like a good
thing. How many of you would like to be
temperate in righteousness? You probably
know not to raise your hand right now
because of what I just
said. But temperance in righteousness,
beloved, let me just break it down for
you. Come on.
Sidebe side. Let's go back to the
screen. Let's go back to the
screen. We're going to go to the parable
found in Matthew 25, beginning with
verse one. The Bible
says, "Then shall the kingdom of heaven
be likened unto 10 virgins, which took
their lamps, and went forth to meet the
bridegroom. And five of them were wise,
and five were foolish. They that were
foolish took their lamps, and took no
oil with them. But the wise took oil in
their vessels with their
lamps. While the bridegroom tarried,
they all slumbered and slept. And at
midnight there was a cry made, "Behold,
the bridegroom cometh. Go ye out to meet
him." Then all those virgins arose and
trimmed their lamps. But the um and the
foolish said unto the wise, "Give us of
your oil, for our lamps are gone out."
The wise answered, saying, Not so, lest
there be not enough for us and you. Go
ye rather to them that sell and buy for
yourselves.
So
um verse
10. And while they went to buy, the
bridegroom came, and they that were
ready went in with him to the marriage,
and the door was shut. Afterward also
the other virgins came, saying, Lord,
open up to
us. But he answered and said unto them,
verily I say unto you, I know you not.
Now, let me ask you a question, y'all.
What did the five foolish virgins not
have? They brought no
what? No oil. They brought no oil. I got
to tell you this. Just just don't don't
mind me. I'm I'm about to give you
another sermon that I'm going to be
preaching at some point. I was in my
class teaching my students
yesterday at Oakwood Academy and we were
looking at the parable of the 10 virgins
and then one of my students asked me,
"So the um this parable is about virgin
oil,
right?" And I looked at him for a second
and it just took me totally back. I was
like, "No, no, no, no, no. This parable
is about 10 virgins who had oil."
And then I started laughing and I was
like, "But you know what
though?" I said, "That's really good,
sir." I said, "You may not realize it,
but you just gave me a sermon
idea because virgin oil is oil that has
impurities in it. Extra virgin oil is
oil that has no impurities in it." And I
began to think to myself, man, the five
wise virgins had extra virgin oil. I'd
like
that. I I told him, I said, "Guys, don't
be surprised if I preach a sermon on
extra virgin oil versus virgin oil with
this parable of the 10 virgins." Anyway,
I digress. I just thought about that as
we're reading this.
So, why did the five wise virgins or
foolish virgins, what happened with
them? Why did they not bring oil? Let me
tell you
why. Listen
y'all. The five foolish
virgins were
thinking not of the
future but of the short term.
Y'all put up one in the chat if you
understand the point that I just
made. They were
temperate. They were
conservative when it came to the
oil. Do y'all understand what I just
said?
They were
temperate in purchasing oil. It's like
they wanted to save
money. So, so I think Jesus is coming
really, really, really soon. I'm going
to go ahead and
prepare for the what I think will happen
very soon. I'm not thinking long term. I
don't want to think long term.
I hope Jesus comes soon. See, we got
many Adventists who hope Jesus comes
soon. And it's a good thing to hope
Jesus comes soon. It's a good thing to
hope Jesus comes soon. But beloved,
there's a problem. There's a problem
with these foolish
virgins because they only bought
enough for what they thought would take
them to the coming of Jesus. Let me say
it this
way. They only wanted just
enough. They were
temperate in their
purchase. They were
conservative in their purchase.
Beloved, not only is it wrong to be
intemperate with sin, it is also wrong
to be temperate with righteousness. Are
y'all catching
me? The five wise virgins sought an
abundance of oil. The five foolish said,
"Listen, just give me enough to make it.
Just give me enough to get
through. Just give me
enough to make it to the
gates. It's what we might call risk
aversion. So risk aversion would be the
tendency to avoid
overinvestment in in the spiritual
preparation due to the fear that
sacrifice may not be necessary or worth
it.
They had a minimal investment strategy.
Again, the same issue with with in
temperance and sin is I'm only concerned
with the now. That same spirit is
carried over in the in the in the realm
of righteousness to where hey, listen,
just give me enough
righteousness to make it to the gates of
heaven.
Just give me enough. I don't want the
abundance. So, here's what this means,
right? The five wise
had lamps. I'm sorry. The five foolish
had lamps, but they didn't have oil.
They weren't concerned about oil. Now,
remember this, beloved. What is oil? Oil
is symbolic of the Holy Spirit.
And what is the what do we just see is
the Holy Spirit. Oh, the Holy Spirit the
fruit of the spirit is love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, gentleness, goodness,
faith, meekness, temperance. Is treating
people with respect. It's treating
people right. It's looking after the
oppressed. So watch
this. The five foolish
virgins knew all about
prophecy. They got the
light. Yeah, we get it. We understand.
But like caring about people
Come on, man. Get out of here with
that woke
stuff. You're caring about the oppress.
Come on, man. We don't have time to care
about the oppressed. Preach the present
truth. Preach the straight truth. Love
people. Ah, don't worry about that. just
give us
enough for what we think is necessary to
make it to the kingdom of
heaven. So, we don't care so much about
the oil. We don't care so much about how
we treat people. We don't care so much
about loving your neighbor. We don't
care so much about about helping the the
the uh the oppressed. We don't care so
much about that feely feely stuff. No.
Third angel's
message, national Sunday
law.
Yes. Are you ready for the coming of
Jesus? And while we have while we have
the the lamp that is burning, there is
no love, there is no joy, there is no
peace, there is no longsuffering, there
is no gentleness. The five foolish
virgins know present truth. The five
foolish virgins have present truth, but
they do not have love. They do not have
mercy. They could care
less.
H. And what that ends up being, beloved,
is it is the same being temperate in
righteousness. Get what I'm saying,
y'all? Being conservative, you know, I
want to conserve. Oh, you know, we don't
need just just give me enough to make it
being t we should seek an abundance in
righteousness.
The five wise virgins had an abundance
of
oil. They had an overflow of oil. That's
what we need to be praying for. Give me
an
overflow. Are y'all following me?
So, so, so yes, it is possible to be
preaching what you consider present
truth. You got the lamp, but you
literally have no
oil. How foolish is
that? You were
temperate when it came to the spirit.
You were temperate. I you got to listen
carefully to what I'm saying because
it's easy to get this confused. What do
you mean temporary? We should be listen
to what I'm saying. Y'all let me
exchange the word for being
conservative. You were
conservative when it came to the Holy
Spirit. You were conservative when it
came to the oil. You were conservative
when you came to love. Oh, but you are
surely abundant in sin. You are surely
abundant in righteousness. you are
surely doing abundant business with the
devil, but when it came to loving
others,
uh, when it came to dealing with the
poor, listen
y'all, somebody I I'm, you know, I'm not
calling any names, but somebody told me
the other day that they they knew I was
getting off track when they saw me do
they saw me do a meeting about trying to
help inner city
people. I was
stunned. They knew I had begun to go off
track. I'm not the same old Pastor
Myers. They knew I had begun to go off
track when I started talking about
helping inner
cities, finding ways that the church can
help people in the inner cities.
How do you respond to that?
How do
you
So, so the bridegroom delays his coming
and what ends up happening is that
delay, that delay
exposes the lack of oil in the five
foolish
virgins. Did y'all catch that?
The delay of the coming of Christ
exposes the lack of
oil in the five foolish virgins. They
didn't want abundancy. They only wanted
sufficiency. It wasn't that they were
rebelling against God. It was just that
they were they were exercising risk
aversion.
They wanted faith in the minimum, not
faith that overflows. Give me just
enough to be ready for the coming of
Jesus. Which means I am really only
concerned about myself, not about
anybody else.
Temperance then, beloved, is not just
the restraint of sin, but the discipline
to invest beyond what seems
necessary. Shall I say that
again? Do I need to repeat that again?
Temperance then is not just the
restraint of
sin but it is the discipline to invest
beyond what seems
necessary. It is a mentality of overflow
versus a mentality of sufficiency.
You see, prophetic delay exposes the
shallow
investor. Let me say it again, y'all.
Prophetic delay exposes the shallow
investor. They don't want to put all
in. So, they are
conservative in what they put in.
Do y'all need a mental
rest? Do y'all need a
break? Do y'all need some time to to let
this saturate your
mind? All right, you got your time right
there. We're about to move on. Let's
let's we're about
to get ready.
Y'all get ready. Listen. The
foolish
calculate enough. What they thought was
enough was based on prophecy, was based
on timing. Hey, we think that he's
coming in this time and we've got just
enough oil for this time. So, that
should be good enough. the wise
calculated enough by trust. In other
words, we're not sure how long he's
going to take, but we're going to be
ready and we're going to be found
doing. The five foolish virgins were
preoccupied with the light, not
realizing that they didn't have the oil.
They were occupied with prophecy, with
understanding, but not showing love,
joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness,
goodness, faith, meekness, temperance.
So that, beloved, even in the time of
trouble, when the time of trouble hits
and they come up to that moment and
realize that, yeah, they understand
prophecy, but whoa, their love is being
severely tested and their joy and their
peace.
They come up to the time of trouble
realizing that they are not sealed.
Truth an intellectual knowledge of truth
is not what seals
you. Something was wrong with their
eyes. You ask somebody, "Man, why would
you make a trade like that? You weren't
seeing
right. Something was wrong with your
eyes. And you want to know what was
wrong with your
eyes? You lacked
oil. You lacked oil. Look at what the
Bible says in Revelation 3:18. I counsel
thee to buy me gold tried in the fire
that thou mayest be rich and white
raignment that thou mayest be clothed
and that the shame of thy nakedness do
not appear and anoint thine eyes with
eyes that you may
see. That you may
see. When we anoint our eyes with eyes,
we are able to see a good deal versus a
bad
deal. A good deal allows you A good deal
allows you to see, man, trade up. Trade
up. Trade up. Hey, I got this sin in my
life and I can trade it up for what God
has in store for me for the future. Let
me trade up. Bad eyes will lead you to
trade down.
Oh
[Music]
man. Yeah, look at that thing. Oh, you
know what? Let me trade down. Not only
would I would it cause you to trade
down, but it will also cause you to be
conservative in your love for God.
Conservative in your love for others.
And you may not even realize that you're
being conservative in your love. You
just think I am all about present
truth. You know what? It is crazy to me
right
now. It is crazy to me right now how the
devil has led Christians to
think that
kindness is some kind
of political
position to be laughed at and mocked
at. It is crazy to
me how Christians, not all Christians,
but so many Christians
today will actually
mock Isaiah
58, helping the needy, helping the
oppressed.
Oh, and yet here we
are. Here we are. Come on, y'all. Check
this out. The five wise virgins have
oil. But I need y'all to see this. Come
with me to second 2 Kings 4:2 and 3.
We're building on this oil thing for
We're still building on this temperate
in righteousness thing. Notice with me 2
Kings 4:2. And Elijah said unto her,
this woman, this widow, what shall I do
for thee? Tell me, what hast thou in thy
house? And she said, thy handmmaid has
not anything in thy house save a pot of
oil. Then he said, Go, borrow thee
vessels abroad. of all thy neighbors,
even empty vessels, borrow not a few.
And when thou art come in, thou shalt
shut the door upon thee, and thou thy
sons, thou thy sons shall pour out all
into the vessels, and thou shalt set
aside that which is full. So she went
from him, shut the door upon her and her
and her sons, who brought the vessels to
her, and she poured out. Watch this,
y'all. And it came to pass when the
vessels were full, that she said unto
her son, "Bring me yet another vessel."
And he said, "There is not another
vessel." And the oil was stayed. Now
watch this. Then she came and told the
man of God, and he said, "Go sell the
oil, pay the debt, and live thou and thy
children off of the
rest." Come on,
y'all. This woman had overflowing oil.
The five wise virgins have they have
overflowing o they have brought ample
oil. In this story with Elijah the woman
has overflowing oil. Why does she have
overflowing oil? Because she has been
pouring out into other
vessels. In fact, in fact, watch this.
We're talking about investment. Watch
this. Uh uh Elisha says to her, "Take
the oil and go and pay your
debt." If this is a if this is a lesson
to us, we need to understand that the
reason God gives us oil is to pay our
debts. Debts? Pastor, what are you
talking about? What debts? Oh, let me
show you. If in case you didn't know,
let me show you. Come on, y'all. Romans
13:8, the Bible says, "Oh, no man
anything but to love one another, for he
that loveth another has fulfilled the
law." Let me ask you a question. Do you
have
debts? Yes or
no? Yes or
no? Do you have debts according to the
Bible?
Yes, you have debts. I have debts. And
what are those debts? To
love. To love. Now, if God is giving us
oil to pay our debts, but we're not
paying our debts, is God going to
continue giving us
oil? Come on, somebody.
If God is giving us oil, if the reason
God has given us oil is so that we can
pay our
debts, but we are not paying our debts,
we are not pouring into others. We are
not loving others. Then is he going to
continue to give us oil? I can tell you
this beloved, the five foolish virgins,
they had no oil because they were not
interested in investing in oil. All they
wanted was
light. All they wanted was intellectual
knowledge of the truth. They didn't care
about fulfilling the
debt to love your neighbor. They didn't
care about
neighbor. All they wanted. And this
beloved, listen to me, is temperate in
righteousness. Hey, you know what? Yeah.
I'm not out there killing people. I'm
not out there lying and stealing. No. I
don't know. I don't do those
things. But guess what? Guess what
you're not
doing? When did we see you and not visit
you in prison? When did we see you and
not feed you? When do we see you and not
give you a drink of water? You see,
beloved, when you when you fa in failing
to pay your debts, God can't he's not
going to continue giving you the oil.
You're not interested in long-term
investments. That's what the oil is for.
The oil is about long-term investment.
You're not
interested. You're being temperate where
you should not be. You're being
conservative where you should not
be.
So, if you're not pouring out into
others, God stops pouring out into you.
Now, come on, y'all. We're almost there.
We're all
listen just come. Just just just let's
go. Let's go. Check this out, y'all.
Luke 6:38. Give and it shall be given
unto you. Good measure, pressed down,
shaken together, and running over.
That's the promise. It's right there.
That's the increase. Give and it shall
be given to you. Pour out, and I'm going
to pour out into you. pay your debts and
I'm gonna keep I'm gonna keep
financially sustaining
you because beloved, check this out. The
cash flow of heaven is
oil. The currency of heaven is oil. The
currency of Babylon is sin. Did y'all
follow that? The currency of heaven is
oil. The currency of Babylon is sin. It
is urgency, fear,
self-preservation,
pleasure. Watch this. In Revelation
14:6, the Bible says, "And I saw another
angel fly in the midst of heaven, having
the everlasting gospel to preach unto
them that dwell on earth, to every
nation, kindred, tongue, and people,
saying with a loud voice, fear God, and
give glory to him, for the hour of his
judgment is come, and worship him that
made the heavens and the earth, the
fountains of waters, or the sea and the
fountains of waters." So, is it fair for
us to say that
heaven is interested in getting the oil
out to the
world? If heaven is interested in
getting the oil out to the world, then
we might say that heaven has an economic
system.
Heaven's economy is based on
oil and and heaven wants people to do
business with heaven, trade with heaven,
trade
agreements. Don't fear, you guys. Don't
fear. Don't fear. Don't fear. Don't
think about anything else you might be
thinking about right now. All right?
Just focus on the me. Heaven is
interested in making trade agreements
with us.
So, heaven has an e an an economic
system. Heaven has a h has a currency
and that currency is the oil. You're
rich if you got a lot of
oil. If you have
oil, you're a
billionaire, a spiritual
billionaire. Okay? So, heaven has an
economic
system. But notice the next verse.
Revelation 148. There follow another
angel saying Babylon has fallen that
great city because she made all nations
drink of the wine of the wrath of her
fornication. Babylon has an economic
system as well. In fact, in fact, if you
look at Revelation 18 verse 11, notice
what it says. And the merchants of the
earth shall weep and mourn over her, for
no man buyth her merchandise anymore.
the merchandise of gold and silver and
precious stones and of pearls and fine
linen and purple and silk and scarlet,
all th and all fine and wood and all
manner of vessels of ivory and all
manner of vessels of most precious wood
and of brass and iron and marble. These
are all the things of Babylon and the
slaves and souls of men. So watch
this. Babylon also has an economic
system and that economic system is based
on urgency. It's based on fear. It's
based on sin. That's Babylon's economic
system. Meaning then, beloved, that in
the time of trouble, the ultimate battle
is going to be the economic system of
Babylon versus the e the economic system
of
heaven. And the question will be, whose
economy are you buying
into? Because what I want you to
understand, beloved, is that every time
we do business with Satan, we're
supporting
Babylon. Every time we are
intemperate with
sin or
temperate with righteousness, we are
doing business with Babylon. Y'all put a
five in the chat. Put a five in the chat
if you catch that bomb.
that was just laid
out. When I am conservative in my
investments in
righteousness, when I am liberal in my
sin, I am doing
business with Babylon. I am I'm
supporting Babylon's economy. Babylon's
economy is built on sin. Every time that
I sin, every time that I that I'm in
tempmperate, every time that I'm not
loving, every time that I'm not
forgiving, I am building up the
community of Babylon. Much like the
Egyptians or the Egyptians used Israel,
the Israelites to build up Egypt, right?
They were slaves in Egypt. will build
and build with straw and brick. And so
every time that I do these things, I'm
building up the
economy of
Babylon. So then, watch this you guys.
Temperance is the declaration that I
will not support Babylon's
economy. I only do business with heaven.
In fact, temperance is a blackout, if
you
will, on doing business with Babylon.
It's a protest. Temperance is an
economic protest against Babylon. Y'all
put a nine in the chat if y'all caught
that bomb just now. This is why the
Bible says, listen y'all, here is the
patience and the faith of the saints.
Here is the patience and the faith of
the saints. Here are they that keep the
commandments of God and the faith of
Jesus. What is the patience of the
saints? It is the temperance power. It
is temperance powered
endurance. The patience of the saints
says I will wait. I'm not going to
purchase Babylon's goods. I will wait. I
am
boycotting. I am boycotting. Now, now,
now we're about to bring this home,
y'all. Because now you can begin to see
something really amazing. Did you know
that both the mark of the beast and the
seal of God both deal with
economy, economic systems? Watch this,
you guys. In Revelation 13:16-1 17, the
Bible says, "And he caused all both
small and great, rich and poor, pre free
and bond to receive a mark in their
forehead or in their their for in their
right hand or in their foreheads, that
no man might buy or sell save he that
had the mark of the name or the the name
of the beast or the number of his name."
So watch this.
in Babylon's system. If you don't
support her system, you cannot buy or
sell. You won't do business with us.
We're going to
boycott anyone who supports the economy
of
heaven. Now, why is that
significant? Because heaven, beloved,
has its own sign or symbol of boycotting
the things of this
world. What is that
thing? It it is the opposite of the mark
of the
beast. And we understand that that thing
that is the opposite of the mark of the
beast is the 7th day Sabbath. And here's
what's interesting about this, beloved.
When you go to Exodus 20:8-10, notice
that it says this. Remember the Sabbath
day to keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thy
labor and do all thy work. But the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God. In it thou shalt not do any
work. Stop for a moment.
The
Sabbath, which is the symbol of God, the
symbol of
heaven, says, "Hey, in the heavenly
economy, in the heavenly
economy, the
Sabbath h the
Sabbath, the Sabbath is God's symbol.
that we do not do business with
Babylon. I'm not buying what Babylon is
selling. Did y'all catch that just now?
The Sabbath is the economic
boycott of the system of
Babylon. The
mark is proof that you've bought into
Babylon. The Sabbath is proof that
you're operating on the kingdom of
heaven's economy.
[Music]
Watch this. Look at the
screen. At the end of time, there are
two economies. There's the beast economy
and there's the lamb's economy. The
beast economy is based on urgency. You
got to buy now to survive. You got to
surv if you want to if you want to
survive, you've got to buy and sell.
It's urgent. The lamb's economy is
delayed. We're going to wait. We're
going to
trust the beast economy. It's now or
never. The lamb's economy, not yet, but
it's coming soon. The beast economy
invests in this world. The lamb's
economy invests in the world to come.
The beast uh economy external
conformity. The lamb's uh economy
internal
conviction. The mark is the ID of the
beast economy. The seal is the idea of
the lamb's
economy. The Sabbath says, "I will not
buy. I will not buy." Come on. Uh, you
got We have Let's Let's come off the
screen because I don't want you to see
this next text yet. The Sabbath,
beloved, the Sabbath is the sign.
The Sabbath is the
sign that says I belong to God's
economy. Now, I need y'all to check this
out because you're about to hear
something about the Sabbath that you may
have never thought about
before. The Sabbath is God training us
to wait on him. Did you hear what I just
said?
Temperance is refusing the urgency of
now and saying, "I'mma wait on the
Lord."
So when we observe the Sabbath, it's God
literally teaching us for 24 hours how
to wait on him, how to be
temperate. Sit
still. Don't buy. I'm training you to
learn not to buy or
sell. I'm training you to practice
denying buying or selling. Why? Because
there's a time coming in which you will
be forced to buy and sell. And I want
you to be like, "Oh, I used to I do that
every seven day. Every seventh day, not
buying and
selling." So in this sense then it is
almost as if on the
Sabbath God is pouring out for us the
oil.
It's like a 24-hour period of God
filling us with the
oil, filling us with love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, gentleness, goodness,
faith, meekness, and temperance. It is a
20 It is like a gas
station that we pull up and we got to
stay there for 24 hours while God fills
us with oil. Now, why is that
significant, beloved? Because, listen to
me, it is when it is God doesn't expect
us to use oil before he's filled us up
with
it. Yeah. That's why that's
why when God creates Adam and Eve on the
sixth day, he doesn't create them on the
first day and then they got to go six
days working and then the He created
them on the sixth day, which means that
their first full day is being filled
with
God. Their first full day is the
Sabbath.
God fills them up and then he says, "Now
go use what I've given
you." So, so, so God is pouring into us
his spirit on that day, the blade, the
day he is blessed and sanctified with
himself. And when I say with himself, I
mean the one who is love, joy, peace,
longs, serving, gentleness, goodness,
faith, me is temperance. And now he
says, "Go use the oil that I have given
you." Now, if you didn't receive oil,
that's a bad
sign because what it says is you only
came for
light. You didn't
come to go pay your
debts. You didn't come to go You didn't
come this Sabbath to go pay your debts.
You just came to get some light. You
just came to get some gossip. Maybe you
just came to get some some present
truth. But you didn't you didn't come to
get filled with the oil. Because if you
came to get filled with the oil, it
would have meant that the week
before you had poured out all the oil I
gave you into
others. And the reason you're coming
back this Sabbath is because you're
coming back because you're like, "God, I
used up all my oil, so I need more. I
got more debts to pay. I got more people
to help. I got more people to to
minister to. So, give me more oil. But
if God is like, "Well, what'd you do
with the oil I gave you last Sabbath?"
"Uh, well, you know, I was working. I
was busy, but I'm here for more." You're
not here for more oil. You're here for
light.
H the reason why many of us don't get
filled is because we're not paying our
debts. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We
are not paying our debts. You
guys, God is asking, "What did you do
with the oil that I gave you? What did
you do with the oil that I gave
you?" So, check this out.
We're almost there. I promise you, we're
almost
there. Listen to me. Sabbathke
keepers, seventh day
keepers. If you're keeping the
Sabbath, but you're doing business with
Babylon, you're not really keeping the
Sabbath.
If you are building up Babylon during
the
week, you're being
inmperate with sin and you're being
temperate in righteousness. You're being
conservative in you're not loving.
You're not you're not experiencing the
overflowing abundance of the Holy Spirit
so that you can pay your debts.
then you are supporting
Babylon. And beloved, if you are
supporting Babylon, you cannot be
keeping the Sabbath. You remember how
the God had to deliver the Israelites
out of Egypt in order for them to keep
the Sabbath. They couldn't keep the
Sabbath while supporting Egypt. While
they were building Pharaoh's kingdom,
they had to come out of Egypt in order
to keep the Sabbath. So what I'm saying
is if you are still building for
Pharaoh, if you are still building for
Babylon, beloved, what is happening is
whatever you're you might be in church
on Saturday, but you're not actually
part of the
boycott. Because what happens, beloved,
in the boycott is six days you're
laboring. Six days you're laboring.
Meaning six days you're pouring oil
out. Six days you're pouring out love,
peace, longsuffering, joy. You're
pouring out the fruit of the spirit. Six
days you are working the works of God.
Six days you are working. And on the
seventh day you come back and you say,
"Man, woo, what a boycott. I've been
boycotting Babylon all week. Boy, it is
beautiful." You know, you tell somebody,
"Hey, we're green. We're we're going to
boycott this company." And then you walk
by and you see that person in the
company. Wait, I I thought you were I
thought you were boycotting. Well, you
know, it was emergency. I had to buy
this. I had to get this
thing. In temperance, I was not able to
help myself.
in temperance. God says,
"Listen, the Sabbath is an economic
boycott against the system of
Babylon." Which means I am not
supporting Babylon with my time, with my
body. I am not supporting Babylon in
anything. So part of supporting Babylon
is anger. Part of supporting Babylon is
unforgiveness. Part of supporting
Babylon economically is is is is is uh
uh you fill in the
blank. It's being
unmerciful. It's ignoring the plight of
other people. All of that is building up
Pharaoh's kingdom. That's the economy of
Babylon. You cannot keep the Sabbath
while supporting the economy of Babylon.
You cannot keep the Sabbath while hating
your brother and sister because in
hating your brother or sister, you are
supporting the econ the e the economy of
Babylon. So what I want you to
understand, beloved, is that the Sabbath
I want you to see the Sabbath as an
economic boycott, a
blackout. All right. All right.
Now, I know I'm preaching longer than
usual, y'all. I think I'm preaching
longer than usual. I don't know how long
I've been on
here, but I got to share this. We got to
look at one more thing. We got to look
at one more thing. Come on. I want you
to know with me. Exodus chapter 32,
verse one. We're about to bring it home,
y'all. Let me just stop saying that,
y'all. I I repent for saying we're
almost done. And we're Let me just stop
saying that because I'm worried about
y'all. Like, if you need to log off, log
off. That's all right. Let I apologize.
I repent for telling you that we were
almost done. I'm just not gonna say
anything. I will just preach and when
I'm done, I'm done. Check this
out. So, in Exodus 32:1, when the people
saw that Moses delayed to come down out
of the mount, they gathered to they
gathered themselves together unto Aaron
and said, "Make us gods." All
right, are y'all ready for this?
Remember what we said about
inmperence. Intemperence cannot handle
delay. Intemperance says now. Now, now
that's what in tempmperance is. It is
now for sin and later for righteousness.
In a funny now for sin, forget about
right. In tempmperance cannot deal with
delay. So in this story in Exodus 32,
Moses goes up the mountain. He's there
for 40 days and the children of Israel
because they are being in tempmperate
meaning they could not handle the delay.
They wanted something now. And what
happened? They they went onto
Aaron and they said, "Make us a golden
calf.
make us a golden calf. They
panicked because the
timeline for Moses to return, for Jesus
to return, the timeline was longer than
they
expected. And so, as a result, they they
set up an image to a beast.
in
tempmperence. Because of
inmperance, they couldn't handle the
delay. Satan got into their ear. We got
to do something now. Jesus isn't coming
back. I mean, Moses isn't coming back.
So, what are we going to do? We got to
build an image to a
beast. So, watch this. Because Jesus
isn't coming back now. Because Jesus
isn't making things better in our
society. Because Jesus isn't fixing the
abortion problem. Because Jesus isn't
fixing the homosexual problem. Because
Jesus isn't fixing the crime problem.
Because Jesus isn't fixing the you fill
in the blank problem. We are going to
build us an image. These be thy gods.
Do y'all see
this? The people got in
tempmperate. Now, while they were being
in temperate, guess what? There was one
tribe who was like, "Nah, we'll
wait." Yes.
Y'all remember, right, the Levites, they
said, "Nah, we" The Levites exercised
temperance while all the other
Israelites, all the other Christians
were like, "Nah, we going to build, we
got to handle this situation." By the
way, what did they say after they built
the golden calf? They said, "Tomorrow is
a feast unto the Lord." So, they
dedicated apostasy to the Lord. It was
in the name of the Lord.
They weren't like, "Hey, let's be
wicked." They just said, "Hey, he's not
returning. He's not handling his
business. He's not handling uh our
concerns. So, we're going to go ahead
and set up our own God. We're going to
go ahead and set up our own image. We're
going to set up an image to the beast."
Why? Because we have to handle these bad
things that are happening in our
society. If if he doesn't do it,
somebody's got to do
it. We can't wait. If we wait any
longer, we'll all be destroyed. will be
killed. They'll take
over. So, we've got to act and we've got
to act now. And beloved, what I'm what
I'm telling you, beloved, is that it is
in temperance that leads to the building
of the image. In fact, Aaron, who was
the
priest, succumbed to the demands of the
people. It was a popular demand.
Look at the
screen. Moses is delayed in Exodus 32.
Under Christian nationalism, Jesus isn't
fixing this nation fast
enough. So, they build an idol in Exodus
32. The Christian nationalists want to
build a visible kingdom.
Apostate Christianity wants to build an
invisible kingdom
now. They claim it was a feast to the
Lord. Apostate Protestantism is doing
this in Jesus
name. It was driven by fear, a sense of
urgency. And beloved, apostate
Christianity has instilled so much fear
in Christians today. If we don't do
something, if we don't do
something, they're going to take
over the
world. And so we better act
now. What did this result
in? It resulted in false worship in
Exodus 32.
What does it result in at the end of
time? It results in false
worship. This delayed their entry into
the promised land. Just as apostate
Protestantism will turn people
away because of the apostasy from the
promised land.
Do you see
why it is so
important to exercise
temperance? To not be
rushed into thinking what you're doing
is
right, to
understand the powerful message. As Mark
just said in the chat, wait on the
Lord. At the time of
trouble, every fruit of the spirit is
going to be tested.
your love, your joy, your peace, your
longsuffering, your gentleness, your
goodness, your faith, your meekness,
your
temperance.
Could it be that the
Sabbath is the day in which God
especially pours out his
spirit, expecting
us expecting
us to go pour it out to others?
And could it be that
if if we haven't been doing that, if as
a people we've been so focused on truth,
on the on the
lamps that we've downplayed the
oil. Could it be
possible that we'll find
ourselves at that
time supporting Babylon's economic
system, not even realizing that we were
supporting Babylon's economic system?
Grieve not the spirit of God whereby you
are sealed unto the day of
redemption. Grieve not that
spirit. Our prayer church ought to be
Lord help me to reflect your character.
Help me to be so
filled overflowing with your
oil that this upcoming week I will
demonstrate the evidence that I've been
filled with
oil. Temperance, beloved, is the
evidence of what God has done for me in
my special time with him.
He's poured himself out into me and now
I'm going out paying my debts. How many
of you would like to go pay your debts?
Put a one in the chat if you would like
to go pay your debts because if you if
you're ready to pay debts, let me tell
you, God is
ready to provide you the
funding. If you're like, "Lord, I got
debts to pay this week." He's like,
"Debts?
I got
you. But don't don't lie to the Lord.
Don't be like, "Lord, give me oil, then
you ain't pay your
debts." He will He will back you. He
will grant He will He will fund your
cause,
y'all. So, if you're like, "Pastor,
okay, how do I do this?" I'm simply
saying this. Listen. Decide that this
week you're going to pay debts. Decide
it. And beloved, I believe that God will
pour his spirit into you
today. It's his Sabbath. He said, "I
want you to honor my day. I want you to
remember
me." He will fill you
today. And as he fills you, you go out
like that woman and say, "All right,
paying my debts." and you come back next
time and be like,
"Lord, let me tell you how many debts
I've paid this week," the Lord be like,
"What? Let me give you
more." Heavenly
Father, thank you for speaking to
us. Thank you, Lord, for showing us
that you've called
us to
wait, to
trust, and to not do business with
Satan, to not do business with
Babylon. So Lord, we're asking one thing
today, and that is that you would fill
us, Lord. That you would fill us so that
we can go out and pay our debts this
week, Lord. that we might come back with
testimonies of the debts we've
paid. Only those that pay their debts
will have enough to live off the rest.
That's what the story said. She paid her
debts and lived off the rest. Lord, help
us to understand that in order to have
enough to live off the rest, we've got
to pay our debts. And if we're serious
about paying our
debts, you will be serious about filling
us with
oil. Lord, help us never to
trade as
Esau, as Eve, or as David. Help us never
to trade away the oil that you have
given us.
Fill us
Lord and may we
boycott the system of
Babylon and remember that symbol of
boycott the Sabbath. May we remember it
is a boycott
against
against supporting and building up the
kingdom of this world.
May we stay faithful and true to that
divine blackout.
Lord, thank you for hearing and
answering this prayer because we ask it
in Jesus name. Amen. And amen. I want to
thank you all
uh for tuning in and um and worshiping
with us today. We are going to put the
link in the chat to the afterglow. And
so I want to invite you to uh to join us
and we're going to talk about the
Sabbath school. We're going to talk
about the the divine service and um you
know whatever whatever lessons you
pulled from it. Uh in fact, we're going
to have a study um on this uh sermon
right after this. So if there were
insights that you caught as you were
listening, please feel free to to join
that afterlow. And uh we look forward to
fellowshipping with you there. And may
God bless you and keep you and fill you
and may you pay those debts is my prayer
in Jesus name. Amen. God bless
you. Thank you for joining us today. If
this is your first time worshiping with
us, please check out our website at
livingmana.urch. We are not just here
for Sabbath service. We have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.
[Music]